<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research and Teaching Companion</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/</link><description>Recent content on Research and Teaching Companion</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Columbia University</copyright><atom:link href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/introduction/</guid><description>Making and Knowing Project Research and Teaching Resources Research and Teaching Companion The Making and Knowing Syllabi, step-by-step Lesson Plans for Hands-On, and sample Student projects included in this Companion to the digital edition Secrets of Craft and Nature in Renaissance France result from our many years of research, teaching, and learning together during the Making and Knowing Project’s construction of the edition and since its publication in 2020.
The graduate students in the course Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World—taught 2014-18—conducted text-, object-, and laboratory-based research that resulted in the edition&amp;rsquo;s approximately 130 essays which interpret, contextualize, and reconstruct the content of Ms.</description></item><item><title>Making &amp; Knowing Syllabi</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</guid><description>The Making and Knowing Project began teaching courses that integrated hands-on activities in 2014. In the course Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World—taught 2014-18—graduate students conducted text-, object-, and laboratory-based research that resulted in the edition&amp;rsquo;s approximately 130 essays which interpret, contextualize, and reconstruct the content of Ms. Fr. 640. The Companion contains syllabi for each of the eight versions of Craft and Science, focused each year on a different theme: Moldmaking and Metalworking; Colormaking (including dyes, pigments, artificial gems, coloring woods and metals, and varnish making); Practical Knowledge: Vernacular Natural History, Practical Perspective, Optics, Mechanics, and Medicine; Ephemeral Art; and Printmaking, Inscription, and Impression.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/about/</guid><description>The Companion The Research and Teaching Companion to digital edition Secrets of Craft and Nature in Renaissance France contains resources, and we hope inspiration, for teachers, researchers, and makers who wish to integrate hands-on and digital components into their classes, research projects, and art practice. They are intended to be used flexibly, and we invite you to adapt and create your own resources to fit your needs.
Making and Knowing Syllabi Syllabi from the Making and Knowing Project can suggest possible readings, discussion prompts, model the integration of hands-on activities with discussion of relevant concepts and texts, and link instructors to resources for hands-on activities.</description></item><item><title>Using M&amp;K Resources</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</guid><description>The Making and Knowing Project has collaborated with many institutions, including University of Glasgow Technical Art History Group, Rhode Island School of Design Glass Department, Brown University History Department, Wake Forest University History and Chemistry Departments [LINK], University of Oregon, Eugene {LINK], Vassar College [LINK], Texas A&amp;amp;M University, and Oberlin Art History {LINK]. Further collaborations with Victoria &amp;amp; Albert Museum/Royal College of Art Postgraduate Program in the History of Design [, and University of Amsterdam Technical Art History and Conservation Training Programs saw our students working in parallel and sometimes by remote co-working on reconstructions and hands-on activities.</description></item><item><title>Credits</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/credits/</guid><description>Introduction In all aspects of research and development, the creation of Secrets of Craft and Nature in Renaissance France has brought together scholars, students, researchers, practitioners, makers, organizers, advisors, developers, instructors, designers, and supporters.
The Edition presents the culmination of over five years of iterative, interdisciplinary, and collaborative work—of countless dedicated and enthusiastic members, individuals, and networks of the Making and Knowing Project.
The Project, and thus the Edition, have more components than a traditional scholarly edition, making recognition and crediting more complex than conventional practices in the humanities.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_dyeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_dyeing/</guid><description>Dyeing Making and Knowing Project researchers have undertaken experiments in dyeing with natural colorants as a way to engage with Ms. Fr. 640 and as a preliminary step to making lake pigments. M&amp;amp;K has organized several community outreach activites on dyeing with natural colorants that can be ported directly into the classroom.
Learning Objectives The activity of dyeing with natural colorants following modernized historical recipes has several potential learning outcomes, which can include:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-historical-recipe-collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-historical-recipe-collection/</guid><description>Guide to historical recipes and collections There are far more sources available in online library collections that you may wish to use instead, below is a sample of sources we found useful in Making and Knowing classes.
We also recommend scouring your institutional library’s holdings for historical items related to food and recipes.
Sources in English Wellcome Ms. 213: A Booke of diuers Medecines, Broothes, Salues, Waters, Syroppes and Oyntementes of which many or the most part haue been experienced and tryed by the speciall practize of Mrs Corlyon.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-instructor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-instructor/</guid><description>Historical Culinary Recipe Reconstruction Cooking is an almost universal activity – it is an art, a craft, a science – and yet most people do it without categorizing it as such. Cooking can provide a way for instructors to introduce hands-on experiments and close textual analysis to their students, many of whom will be used to following instructions from recipes and may feel more comfortable engaging in a hands-on activity in a kitchen than a studio, lab, or classroom.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-student/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-student/</guid><description>Historical Culinary Recipe Reconstruction – Student Activity Sheet Do the required reading and watching before you start your reconstruction. Explore and use the websites listed here to search for comparable recipes in contemporaneous sources.
Required Reading/Watching/Listening (do this first) Ken Albala, “Cooking as Research Methodology: Experiments in Renaissance Cuisine,” Renaissance Food from Rabelais to Shakespeare: Culinary Readings and Culinary Histories, ed. Joan Fitzpatrick (Aldershot, UK: Ashgate, 2010), pp. 73–88.
Syrup of Violets and Science video (ca 8 mins).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/</guid><description>Making Lake Pigments The Making and Knowing Project has used lake pigment making as a core skill-building exercise for its students. M&amp;amp;K has often assigned lake pigment making alongside verdigris growing, which were then followed up by a paint making and testing activity. Nevertheless, lake pigment making can be done on its own.
Learning Objectives The activity of making lake pigments from modernized historical recipes has several potential learning outcomes, which can include:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_paintingpigments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_paintingpigments/</guid><description>Making and Testing Paints Made by Hand from Pigments The Making and Knowing Project has used paint and test card making as a core skill-building exercise for its students. Paint making has often been a follow-up activity to lake pigment making or verdigris growing, but paint making can also be undertaken using commercially produced pigments.
Learning Objectives The activity of making paint and testing out those paints on a sample card has several potential learning outcomes, which can include:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_varnishes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_varnishes/</guid><description>Making Varnishes The Making and Knowing Project has reconstructed varnish recipes several times, both to produce varnishes as ends in themselves and to produce them as ingredients in more complex making processes described in Ms. Fr. 640. The manuscript includes several recipes for spirit varnishes, which were a new category of varnish that emerged in the sixteenth century. It also includes several recipes for oil-based varnishes, which have a longer history and are quite dangerous to reconstruct.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/azurite-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/azurite-assignment/</guid><description>Skillbuilding: Preparing and Painting with Azurite The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2022-11-30 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Presentations &amp;amp; Handouts Presentation: Preparing and Painting Blue Pigment in the Renaissance See also a short version of this presentation Student Handout (to have while doing the hands-on reconstruction) Introduction This skillbuilding assignment will introduce you to one of the most common blue pigments in the Renaissance, azurite.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding-assignment/</guid><description>BREAD MOLDING RECONSTRUCTION ASSIGNMENT HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-08-19
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
The 16th-century artisanal/technical manual, BnF Ms. Fr. 640, contains hundreds of entries that describe making processes and techniques from the Renaissance. These include instructions for and observations about painting, gilding, arms and armor production, plant cultivation, and making molds and metal casts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding-student-activity-sheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding-student-activity-sheet/</guid><description>Class Activity: Breadmolding Objectives explore historical breadmaking recipes and techniques
learn to bake bread
produce loaves of bread to use as molds
This activity has two parts
Part 1 (at home before class): learn about baking bread and produce loaves to use as molds for a small object
Part 2 (in class): pour wax (and/or sulfur) into your molds, unmold
Part 1 – making bread and molding (at home, in advance) Materials flour</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding_resources-for-the-instructor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding_resources-for-the-instructor/</guid><description>Breadmolding Introduction The 16th-century artisanal/technical manual, BnF Ms. Fr. 640, contains hundreds of entries that describe making processes and techniques from the Renaissance. These include instructions for and observations about painting, gilding, arms and armor production, plant cultivation, and making molds and metal casts.
Ms. Fr. 640 contains three mentions of bread as a material that can be used to take an impression of another object quickly and neatly. This impression can be used as a mold into which sulfur or wax is cast.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/burnsalve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/burnsalve/</guid><description>Activity: Reconstruction of a 16th-Century Burn Salve Recipe The study of historical recipes or &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rdquo; instructions can be a powerful tool to engage with the past and to learn about daily life in a different, more tangible way than traditional textual sources. Historical reconstruction &amp;ndash; attempting to follow or replicate the recipe &amp;ndash; can bring the past to life and provide new perspectives for experts and students alike.
The activity sheet and resources below are intended to invite you to undertake a hands-on historical reconstruction yourself, or to provide you with what you will need to bring this activity into your classroom, studio, or even kitchen.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-assignment/</guid><description>Dyeing with Natural Colorants: Resources and Activity Sheets Resources for dyeing textiles with natural colorants (including cochineal, madder, weld, and redwoods) following historical dye recipes. Recipes and procedure adapted from Jo Kirby et al, Natural Colorants for Dyeing and Lake Pigments: Practical Recipes and their Historical Sources (Archetype, London, 2014) (2022-06-17)
Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation - an overview of historical natural colorants and dyes, details about common red colorants, a deep-dive into the history of cochineal insects as a dye and pigment source, the preparation of mordant dyes, and explanation of the chemistry of these natural colorants</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-cochineal_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-cochineal_assignment/</guid><description>Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal: A Historical Reconstruction The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2023-03-30 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Dyes and natural colorants If you are not already familiar with historical dyes and natural colorants, refer to Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation for more complete information and further explanation of natural colorants and dyeing.
A dye is &amp;ldquo;a compound that absorbs into and colors another material&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;is generally a complex organic material&amp;rdquo; (Conservation and Art Materials Encyclopedia Online (CAMEO)).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/painting-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/painting-assignment/</guid><description>Making Paints from Pigments and Painting Them Out HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-05-13 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Paint = Pigment + Binding Media Refer to Presentation: Introduction to Pigments &amp;amp; Paints
Overview of Activity Much more detailed information and resources are provided below in this document. To help get you started, this is an overview of the hands-on work and preparation you will do:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-cochineal-lake_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-cochineal-lake_assignment/</guid><description>MAKING LAKE PIGMENT FROM COCHINEAL: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-09-29 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Lake pigments and natural colorants If you are not already familiar with historical pigments and natural colorants, refer to Presentation: Cochineal Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation for more complete information and further explanation of natural colorants and lake pigments.
See also Presentation: Introduction to Pigments &amp;amp; Paints.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-madder-lake_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-madder-lake_assignment/</guid><description>MAKING LAKE PIGMENT WITH MADDER: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2022-01-29 by NJR
Refer also to:
Presentation: Cochineal Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation - while this is for a different colorant (cochineal), the chemistry of lakes is the same. Making Pigment from Madder: a Trio of Recipes - helpful step-by-step fieldnotes for all three recipes Lake pigments are a type of pigment prepared from organic natural colorants: plant and animal sources.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt-2/</guid><description>Secrets of Craft and Nature Reconnaissance (Directed Scavenger Hunt) A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
BnF Ms. Fr. 640 has 170 folios (340 pages) with over 900 entries on metalworking, casting, painting, medicine, and sleight of hand tricks. This is an exercise with two activities to help become familiar with the online Edition and Translation of Ms. Fr. 640: Secrets of Craft and Nature.
Activity 1: Explore the Manuscript Folios Choose a linked folio from below and find:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt_secrets-of-craft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt_secrets-of-craft/</guid><description>Scavenger Hunt: Get to know Secrets of Craft and Nature Browse the online Edition of Ms. Fr. 640: Secrets of Craft and Nature.
Explore each menu item.
Complete the scavenger hunt of the Edition
Pick three of the following terms (or another term of your choosing), and use the search bar to search the manuscript: &amp;ldquo;mercury,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;bread,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;rat,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;dog,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;cuttlefish,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;saliva,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;garlic,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;blood,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;rosemary,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;milk,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;horse,” “earwax” Browse the results and select one of the occurrences in the manuscript that you find interesting.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp22_fld_rosenkranz_naomi_madder-lake-trio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp22_fld_rosenkranz_naomi_madder-lake-trio/</guid><description>MAKING LAKE PIGMENT WITH MADDER: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2022-01-29 by NJR
Refer (insert something like &amp;ldquo;refer to the assignment sheet&amp;rdquo; instead of what&amp;rsquo;s here, keep jo kirby info though) also to Presentation: Cochineal Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation - while this is for a different colorant (cochineal), the chemistry of lakes is the same. (this was an experiment to try all three different recipes, each of which is listed below)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp23_dyes_tamu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp23_dyes_tamu/</guid><description>BioArt Workshop: Dyeing with Cochineal Bugs The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2023-03-24 by NJR
Texas A&amp;amp;M PVFA/BIOL BioArt Workshop March 21–24, 2023 Organized by Tianna Uchacz with Donna Janes and Naomi Rosenkranz
Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation
Handouts Dyeing Instructions - General Process for Mordanting and Dyeing Textiles Summary of Dye Samples and Measurements Recipe Example: De&amp;rsquo; secreti del reverendo signore Alessio Piemontese (1558) Summary of Materials and Samples Name Mordant Dye NC None Cochineal NCP None Cochineal + potash AC Alum Cochineal ACP Alum Cochineal + potash IC Iron sulphate Cochineal CC Copper sulphate Cochineal Textiles</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco-assignment/</guid><description>STUCCO FOR MOLDING RECONSTRUCTION HIST GR8906: Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World | Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-09-24 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
NOTE TO INSTRUCTORS: Rather than providing the full instructions, one may want to provide students only with the original recipe and the materials, allowing them to interpret the entry for themselves.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco_assignment_student-handout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco_assignment_student-handout/</guid><description>STUCCO FOR MOLDING RECONSTRUCTION - STUDENT HANDOUT HIST GR8906: Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World | Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-09-24 by NJR
Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640 The 16th-century artisanal/technical manual, BnF Ms. Fr. 640, contains hundreds of entries that describe making processes and techniques from the Renaissance. These include instructions for and observations about painting, gilding, arms and armor production, plant cultivation, and making molds and metal casts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su17_rosenkranz_azurite-preparation-cambridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su17_rosenkranz_azurite-preparation-cambridge/</guid><description>June 5, 2017
Azurite crushing and washing session
Led by Spike Bucklow
Fitzwilliam studio room
Notes by NJR (Naomi Rosenkranz)
Flickr album of&amp;gt; Azurite_NJR
V&amp;amp;A/RCA blog post on Azurite May 2017 part&amp;gt; 1
V&amp;amp;A/RCA blog post on Azurite May 2017 part&amp;gt; 2
Cambridge University
“Genius Before Romanticism”
Workshop organized by the Ingenuity Project (Alex Marr) with the Making Visible Project (S. Kusukawa) and the curatorial team of the Fitzwilliam Museum’s “Madonnas and Miracles” exhibit (March - June 2017)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</guid><description>Dyeing with Onion Skins Annika Cunningham, summer and fall 2021
Introduction My name is Annika Cunningham, and I am a high schooler in Boston. I have been weaving, knitting, and crocheting for over a decade, and also enjoy exploring the scientific methods behind these crafts. I wanted to experiment with dye-making techniques using more affordable and accessible materials, like onion skins!
Onions originated in Asia and the Middle East, but the exact period and geographic origin are uncertain.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/</guid><description>VERDIGRIS PIGMENT &amp;ldquo;GROWING&amp;rdquo; RECONSTRUCTION HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-08-19 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Safety Note: Nitrile/latex gloves must be worn when handling verdigris. Do not touch your mouth or bare skin. Do not scrape or grind the verdigris on food preparation surfaces.
Verdigris is a blue-green pigment prepared by exposing copper to acetic acid (vinegar), forming a basic copper acetate.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_alberts_naomi_final-project_ph-lesson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_alberts_naomi_final-project_ph-lesson/</guid><description>Instructor Assignment Sheet: Ms. Fr. 640 fol. 43v, “Varied and Transmuted Wine” by Naomi Alberts, Fall 2021
Objective: Introducing and explaining concepts related to pH to students. pH testing refers to determining how acidic or basic a water-based solution is. Additionally, getting students to think about the physical property of color and what a change in color can tell an observer. Finally, making historical connections between pre-Scientific Revolution and current/modern scientific views, while also exploring the “boundaries and relationship between seventeenth-century art and science.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_atkins+joyce-farley_charlotte+siobhan_pranks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_atkins+joyce-farley_charlotte+siobhan_pranks/</guid><description>An Exploration of Humor in Ms. Fr. 640 Charlotte Atkins and Siobhan Joyce-Farley, Fall 2021
When we decided to recreate and record riddles from Ms. Fr. 640 for our final project, our major interests were exploring accessible entry points into the manuscript and thinking about how modes of entertainment have and haven’t evolved across location and history. We thought that riddles and practical jokes would be easy to recreate authentically, and we assumed that their societal function would have stayed relatively fixed across time.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_coutavas_allie_final-project-reds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_coutavas_allie_final-project-reds/</guid><description>The Color Red in Ms. Fr. 640 Alexandra Coutavas
Fall 2021, Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Bibliothèque nationale de France Ms. Fr. 640 is a late sixteenth-century manuscript containing instructions, recipes, and practical notes on a variety of subjects pertaining to crafts. As a text dealing with art making and materials, the names of colors and pigments appear frequently throughout. Using Carl Garris’ “What is Azur in Ms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_ghoneima_hana_final-project-oral-culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_ghoneima_hana_final-project-oral-culture/</guid><description>Oral Culture in Ms. Fr. 640 Hana Ghoneima
Making and Knowing Project, Fall 2021
BnF Ms. Fr. 640 stands at the intersection of a pivotal moment in history, in which craftspeople who were previously illiterate began recording their procedures and trade in writing.1 Within this context, Ms. Fr. 640 is an illuminating document not only for its content on craft techniques, but for the historical milestones and trends it embodies. One of those is oral culture, and its intersection with the written one.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_jacobson_beah_final-project-know/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_jacobson_beah_final-project-know/</guid><description>Textual Analysis of Instances of “To Know” in Ms. Fr. 640 Beah Jacobson, Fall 2021
On folio 125r of BnF Ms. Fr. 640, the phrase “a sçavoir” appears circled and set off from a stream of surrounding marginal text on plaster; its placement suggests that it may accompany the folio’s “Scimitars” entry. Combined with an auxiliary “a,” this phrase is somewhat more enigmatic than the straightforward English infinitive “to know,” as translated in the Digital Critical Edition of the Making &amp;amp; Knowing Project.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_lin+sundar_danli+anusha_final-project_regimens-remedies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_lin+sundar_danli+anusha_final-project_regimens-remedies/</guid><description>Regimens, Recipes, and Remedies: Understanding the “Cosmetic” in Early Modern Europe Danli Lin and Anusha Sundar
Fall 2021, Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Introduction A Google search of the word “cosmetic” yields many meanings, including anything related to beautification, correcting defects, decorating, and clearing one’s complexion. We are also immediately reminded of beauty models, or the scores of beauty products that line the aisles of supermarkets. There is also the endless barrage of advertisements featuring glistening hair, glowing skin, and miraculously spot-free skin!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_steinman_charlie_final-project-ms262/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_steinman_charlie_final-project-ms262/</guid><description>Transcribing, Translating, and Encoding MS Gen, 262: Sefer Refu&amp;rsquo;os u-Segulos / Book of Remedies and Incantations Charlie Steinman Fall 2021
About the MS Columbia MS Gen. 262 is a collection of recipes and other instructional texts written by a Yiddish-speaking, Jewish practitioner in Northern Italy around 1470. The bulk of the manuscript is in a dialect of Old Western Yiddish, bearing witness to the increasing presence of Jews from the German-speaking lands in Italy.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_weisgall_benjamin_final-project-architecture-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_weisgall_benjamin_final-project-architecture-workshop/</guid><description>The Making and Meaning of Intermediates: Workshop and Syllabus for Students of Architecture Benjamin Weisgall
Screen capture from “How was it made? Plaster cast” by the V&amp;amp;A Museum
The following six-week unit is designed for students of art and architecture and others who are already comfortable in the workshop (la boutique) but may be less familiar with the uses and pleasures of historical study (quelque histoire). Using the digital critical edition of Ms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_zayas+waters_elliot+mac_final-project-soundscape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_zayas+waters_elliot+mac_final-project-soundscape/</guid><description>The Soundscape of Process: An Audio Recreation of Lifecasting in the Workshop Elliot Zayas and Mac Waters, Fall 2021
In the introduction to his history of audio reproduction technologies, Jonathan Sterne outlines the supposed supremacy of visual concerns in many of the primary cultural academic disciplines. From the obsession with the “gaze” to the primacy of the visual object, visual cultures have dominated scholarship for centuries. Musicologist Kate Galloway expands this observation to the recent developments of the digital humanities, noting that “the digital humanities continues to be astonishingly silent” (Galloway, 47), prioritizing visual and literary scholarship.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_arocho_alejandra_herodotus-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_arocho_alejandra_herodotus-workshop/</guid><description>Herodotus’ ‘Workshop’: A Core (Curriculum) Pathway into Ms. Fr. 640 and its Author-Practitioner Alejandra Quintana Arocho Professor Pamela Smith | Naomi Rosenkranz | Caroline Surman Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-on History 10 May 2022
This project is directed toward Columbia College and General Studies students who have taken the course &amp;ldquo;Literature Humanities&amp;rdquo; (Lit Hum) as part of Columbia&amp;rsquo;s Core Curriculum and want to see how an author/artisan from Renaissance Toulouse participates in their ongoing literary/scholarly conversations.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_bergen+sabet_jamie+sofia_final-project_grotto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_bergen+sabet_jamie+sofia_final-project_grotto/</guid><description>Jamie Bergen and Sofia Sabet
Spring 2022, GU4962: Hands-on History
Creating a “Modern” Reconstruction of a Miniature Grotto Grottos imitate a spring, often located in a cave-like structure, and usually contain fountains, sculpture, and imitation flora and fauna.
Engraving of a grotto in the gardens of Hortus Palatinus, Heidelberg, from Salomon de Caus’ Hortus Palatinus. Engraving done by Matthieu Marian’s (1620), https://digi.ub.uni-heidelberg.de/diglit/caus1620/0034/image,info,thumbs
In L&amp;rsquo;Idea della Architettura Universale (The Idea of a Universal Architecture), published in 1615, Italian architect Vincenzo Scamozzi described “grotto porticos” that were decorated with “pebbles [and] tuff and other materials petrified in various shapes of nature…and then decorated here and there with niches, with statues of stone and sometime of metal.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_donald_maia_final-project_cuttlebone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_donald_maia_final-project_cuttlebone/</guid><description>Cuttlefish in and around Ms. Fr. 640 Maia Donald
Spring 2022
Cuttlebone, the hard interior shell of the cuttlefish, has a long history of human use. While today it is primarily consumed as a calcium supplement by pet birds and reptiles, cuttlebone was long ago used as a polishing powder, casting material, and carving medium. Both Aristotle and Pliny offer detailed examinations of cuttlefish in their more general overview of cephalopods.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_gardner_schuyler_final-project-sieves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_gardner_schuyler_final-project-sieves/</guid><description>Sieves in Ms. Fr. 640 Schuyler Gardner
Spring 2022, GU4962: Hands-on History
In early modern Europe, the line between tools used in workshops and in kitchens was blurred. Tools that crossed these spaces can reveal how people, particularly women, could negotiate their identities within different early modern spaces. In Ms. Fr. 640, there is a distinct interest in tools that rest at this intersection. Whether through the illustrations of furnaces (fol.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_lang_theodora_counterproofing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_lang_theodora_counterproofing/</guid><description>Counterproofing: Reproduction and Theft in Early Modern Print Culture Theodora Bocanegra Lang Spring 2022 Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
In an entry of BnF Ms. Fr. 640 entitled “Counterproofing” (folio 51r, the author-practitioner provides the reader with instructions on how to copy a print using a method of the same name that entails wetting the print and pressing it onto a fresh piece of paper in an attempt to dampen the ink and ultimately transfer the image.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_nebolsin_victoria_final-project_animal-rationality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_nebolsin_victoria_final-project_animal-rationality/</guid><description>Animal Rationality in Ms. Fr. 640 Victoria Nebolsin
Making and Knowing: Hands-On History
May 2022
Ms. Fr. 640 reveals a surprisingly symbolic treatment of some of the animals with which the author-practitioner engages. While overall the manuscript possesses a mostly practical, straightforward approach, several passages on animals display language that sings with metaphor. Snakes are explicitly compared to Satan (fol. 109v), rats are compared to the tyrant of Syracuse 152r), and pigs can understand Greek (13v).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_wei+yang_jianing+luxi_popup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_wei+yang_jianing+luxi_popup/</guid><description>Making and Knowing Pop-up Book Luxi Yang and Jianing Wei Spring 2022 HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
A Visual Presentation of the Pop-up Book [PDF]
Behind the scenes This final project for the course &amp;ldquo;Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&amp;rdquo; at Columbia University was created by Luxi Yang and Jianing Wei.
This pop-up book contains both a selection of entries from Ms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown-reece_final-project_dye-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown-reece_final-project_dye-workshop/</guid><description>Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal Reece Brown
Spring 2023
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
My project takes the form of a workshop that teaches the process of dyeing to a group of 10 high school students. This endeavor promotes hands-on artisanal production that connects materials to their effects, integrating the different stages in the process into the different forms that the materials assume.
This workshop explores cochineal from three different disciplines: biology, chemistry, and history.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown_reece_final-project_dye-workshop-instructor-lab-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown_reece_final-project_dye-workshop-instructor-lab-guide/</guid><description>Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal Lab Guide for Instructors Reece Brown
Spring 2023
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Plant Based Dyes: The Chemistry of Cochineal This workshop was created to teach the process of dyeing to a group of high school students in an environmental science class. This workshop promotes hands-on artisanal production and helps students see the various effects and uses of natural materials, showing how the different stages in the process bring about different forms of the material.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown_reece_final-project_dye-workshop-student-lab-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown_reece_final-project_dye-workshop-student-lab-guide/</guid><description>Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal Lab Guide for Students Reece Brown
Spring 2023
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Adapted from chapter 5, “Recipes,” of Jo Kirby et al, Natural Colorants for Dyeing and Lake Pigments: Practical Recipes and their Historical Sources (Archetype, London, 2014).
MATERIALS Dyestuff (cochineal)
mordant (alum)
Mortar and pestle
Coffee filter
Water
Textile - 25 g cotton bandana
Thermometer
Stirring stick
Plate</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_fan_ruilin_final-project_flesh-color/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_fan_ruilin_final-project_flesh-color/</guid><description>“Flesh Color” and Race Making in Early Modern Painters’ Manuals Ruilin Fan Spring 2023 HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
BnF Ms. Fr. 640 contains a number of recipes for making pigments and paints. Among them, the author-practitioner is especially interested in “flesh color (carnation),” providing 18 entries that mention this category of colors. It is evident from the diverse instructions contained in these recipes that flesh color is not a singular skin tone but refers to a range of colors that may represent various human complexions.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_lambert-avery_final-project_medieval-spirituality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_lambert-avery_final-project_medieval-spirituality/</guid><description>Medieval Spirituality and Materiality in Ms. Fr. 640 Avery Lambert Spring 2023 HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
The author-practitioner of Ms. Fr. 640 compiled his recipe-book in a period of great religious, political, and social turmoil. Southern France in the late sixteenth-century was a hotbed of conflict amidst the Wars of Religion, during which competing religious ideas challenged older beliefs and traditions. But where in this early modern world, and in Ms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_narcy_gilles_final-project_languages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_narcy_gilles_final-project_languages/</guid><description>Languages and Linguistic Agency in Ms. Fr. 640 Gilles Narcy Spring 2023 HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Introduction: Languages as practical knowledge This essay focuses on the role played by languages in Ms. Fr. 640. Although written in French, as its call number in the Bibliothèque nationale de France’s catalogue indicates, it contains several occurrences of other languages. Extensive scholarship has been dedicated to artisan authors and the rise of books of recipes in the early modern era, focusing on the difficulties and paradoxes of putting embodied, practical knowledge into writing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_nelkin-nesya_final-project_candles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_nelkin-nesya_final-project_candles/</guid><description>Candles: Making and Breaking Boundaries in Early Modern Jewish and Christian Ritual Nesya Nelkin Spring 2023 HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Candles and their materials are ubiquitous in BnF Ms. Fr. 640. The author-practitioner suggests their use in activities as far-ranging as melting and cutting glass, smoking molds, to burning off small hairs from animals to be life-cast, to catching birds.1 Beeswax and tallow (made by rendering suet, the organ fat of beef, lamb, or mutton), both very versatile substances and common candle materials, appear even more frequently, for purposes including molding, healing, food preservation, and portraiture.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_oberem-lukas_final-project_varnish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_oberem-lukas_final-project_varnish/</guid><description>Varnishing, a Craft of Closure Lukas Oberem Spring 2023 HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Le vernis racoustre tout cela &amp;amp; lunist &amp;amp; rend semblable aulta(n)t en un endroit quen laultre.
The varnish mends all this and unites and renders it similar in one place as in another.1
As a very last step, an artisan adds varnish to a work of craft. With this small addition, we may say, the work receives its last touch.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_rao-sumant_final-project_puffball/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_rao-sumant_final-project_puffball/</guid><description>Puffball Mushrooms and Early Modern Race-Making: A Skin-Whitening Recipe in BnF Ms. Fr. 640 Sumant Rao Spring 2023 HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Introduction In Thomas Heywood’s and Richard Brome’s play The Late Lancashire Witches (1634), a wedding party is awaiting an extravagant banquet; suddenly, after the host reads out the menu, a woman runs on stage and exclaims that their feast has undergone a horrible transformation:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_shi-jingxian_final-project_paintbrushes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_shi-jingxian_final-project_paintbrushes/</guid><description>European Paintbrushes and Chinese Ink Brushes in the Early Modern World Jingxian Shi Spring 2023 HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
Introduction Chinese ink brushes have become inextricably intertwined with writing culture, evolving into a symbol of literacy and the mastery of Chinese characters. Some scholars assert that the Chinese ink brush is unique as the only soft-tip brush in existence in the early modern period.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_branscum_elizabeth_final-project-medicinal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_branscum_elizabeth_final-project-medicinal/</guid><description>Medicine in Ms. Fr. 640 and Household Recipe Books Elizabeth Branscum
Summer 2021
Introduction As you know by now, the origin and purpose of BnF Ms. Fr. 640 is still uncertain. Who is the mysterious author-practitioner who compiled these recipes, and what did he intend to do with them? Part of what makes this question so intriguing is the inclusion of recipes on such a wide variety of topics – craft, sleight of hand, and even medicine.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_christensen_anna_final-project-natural-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_christensen_anna_final-project-natural-things/</guid><description>Understanding Natural Things in the World and the Workshop Anna Christensen
Summer 2021
The lifecasting and preservation practices that appear in BnF Ms. Fr. 640 are a window into the understanding of the natural world through craft practice during the sixteenth century. Animals that appear as casts or natural historical specimens in the manuscript include frogs and toads, snakes, lizards, turtles, flies, spiders, beetles, crabs, crayfish, bats, rats, cats, and birds of various kinds.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_fox_mackenzie_final-project-disorganization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_fox_mackenzie_final-project-disorganization/</guid><description>Was Ms. Fr. 640 Intentionally Disorganized? Mackenzie Fox
Summer 2021
When browsing through the wide range of how-to instructions in BnF Ms. Fr. 640, it is often frustratingly unclear why the author-practitioner chose to address such disparate topics in a single text, or why he chose to arrange them in such an apparently random way. Why, for instance, does he, in the space of a single page, give advice on how to prepare earth for making molds to cast metal, record an observation about the ways in which garden lilies grow and flower, offer yet further advice on the appropriate type of earth for use in casting, and, finally, discuss the rate at which ducklings grow and how one should feed them?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_macomber_sophie_final-project-figures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_macomber_sophie_final-project-figures/</guid><description>Pictures Worth 1,000 Words: Figures and their Uses in Ms. Fr. 640 Sophie Macomber
Summer 2021
Have you ever tried following a new recipe that didn't have any pictures? Not even a picture of the end result? It's hard, right?! While pictures might seem to add clutter when you're just trying to figure out how much water to add to four cups of flour or exactly to what temperature the oven needs to be set, they can be meaningful tools for communicating other kinds of information, and their use in instruction manuals and notebooks dates back centuries (see also Leonardo Da Vinci's notebooks for a contemporaneous example of the use of figures), as can be seen in Ms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</guid><description>Dyeing with Onion Skins Annika Cunningham, summer and fall 2021
Introduction My name is Annika Cunningham, and I am a high schooler in Boston. I have been weaving, knitting, and crocheting for over a decade, and also enjoy exploring the scientific methods behind these crafts. I wanted to experiment with dye-making techniques using more affordable and accessible materials, like onion skins!
Onions originated in Asia and the Middle East, but the exact period and geographic origin are uncertain.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</guid><description>HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History HIST GU4962 Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History Tuesdays 10:10am-12:00pm
Instructor: Prof. Pamela Smith
Assistant Director, Making and Knowing Project: Naomi Rosenkranz
Project and Communications Coordinator, Making and Knowing Project: Caroline Surman
This course is associated with the Making and Knowing Project of the Center for Science and Society at Columbia University. Please sign up for announcements for both on the websites!</description></item></channel></rss>