<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research and Teaching Companion</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/</link><description>Recent content on Research and Teaching Companion</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Columbia University</copyright><atom:link href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction-to-the-research-and-teaching-companion">Introduction to the Research and Teaching Companion&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="research-and-teaching-companion">Research and Teaching Companion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This Research and Teaching Companion is intended to support you in engaging with hands-on experimentation in your teaching, research, and/or artistic practice and making.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The resources included in this Companion to the digital edition &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/">&lt;em>Secrets of Craft and Nature in Renaissance France&lt;/em>&lt;/a> result from many years of research, teaching, and learning together during the &lt;a href="https://www.makingandknowing.org/">Making and Knowing Project&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s creation of the edition (2014-2020) and since its publication in 2020.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making &amp; Knowing Syllabi</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-and-knowing-project-syllabi">Making and Knowing Project Syllabi&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Syllabi from the Making and Knowing Project can be used to suggest possible readings, discussion prompts, model the integration of hands-on activities with seminar-style discussion of relevant concepts and texts, and connect instructors to resources for hands-on activities. These syllabi contain links to the edition&amp;rsquo;s approximately 130 &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/essays">essays&lt;/a> which can be used as course readings or to instruct in reconstructions (also useful for this are &lt;a href="https://fieldnotes.makingandknowing.org">field notes&lt;/a>). Making and Knowing Syllabi can also be mined for their &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/">Lesson Plans&lt;/a>, while the &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/">Student Projects&lt;/a> from Hands-On History courses can be consulted by instructors and students for inspiration in planning papers and projects, and to consider the many ways to engage with Ms. Fr. 640 and the digital edition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About M&amp;K</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/about/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-making-and-knowing-project">The Making and Knowing Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.makingandknowing.org/">Making and Knowing Project&lt;/a>, founded in 2014 by Pamela H. Smith and involving hundreds of collaborators, is a research and pedagogical initiative in the &lt;a href="https://scienceandsociety.columbia.edu">Center for Science and Society&lt;/a> at Columbia University. The Project explores the intersections between historical craft making and scientific knowing. Drawing on techniques from both laboratory and archival research as well as studio practice and the digital humanities, the Making and Knowing Project aims to cross the science/humanities divide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>M&amp;K Resources in Use</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-and-knowing-resources-in-use">Making and Knowing Resources in Use&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Making and Knowing Project has many &lt;a href="https://www.makingandknowing.org/collaborators/">collaborators&lt;/a> from K-12 to university, to non-traditional schools and public outreach institutions, who have piloted the Making and Knowing Project&amp;rsquo;s methods, course elements, and lesson plans in their research projects, courses, and student activities. The fruits of their experience, their syllabi, student projects, and making activities are valuable for those seeking to integrate Making and Knowing resources into their teaching and research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Credits</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/credits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/credits/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="credits">Credits&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In the development of the Making and Knowing Project&amp;rsquo;s Research and Teaching Companion, many individuals have contributed, including instructors, scholars, students, researchers, practitioners, makers, organizers, advisors, developers, designers, and supporters. The Companion represents the culmination of many years of iterative, interdisciplinary, and collaborative work by countless dedicated and enthusiastic members, individuals, and networks of the &lt;a href="https://www.makingandknowing.org/">Making and Knowing Project&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="research-and-teaching-companion-contributors">Research and Teaching Companion Contributors&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="senior-editorial-team-for-the-companion">Senior Editorial Team for the Companion&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Naomi Rosenkranz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pamela H. Smith&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tianna Helena Uchacz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Terry Catapano&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="senior-digital-team-for-the-companion">Senior Digital Team for the Companion&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Terry Catapano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Nick Laiacona and team at &lt;a href="https://www.performantsoftware.com/">Performant Software Solutions&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Naomi Rosenkranz&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="planning-and-implementation-for-the-companion">Planning and Implementation for the Companion&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pamela H. Smith&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Naomi Rosenkranz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tianna Helena Uchacz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tillmann Taape&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sophie Pitman&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Donna Bilak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Terry Catapano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Caroline Surman&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gregory Schare&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/2024_RTC_Worksprint.jpg" alt="Companion Worksprint">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_dyeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_dyeing/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dyeing">Dyeing&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Making and Knowing Project has undertaken experiments in dyeing with natural colorants as a way to engage with various entries in Ms. Fr. 640 and as a preliminary step to &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/">making lake pigments&lt;/a>. Additionally, M&amp;amp;K has led several community outreach activites on dyeing with natural colorants that can be ported directly into the classroom. These activities and their contexts are also described on the &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/">Making and Knowing Resources in Use&lt;/a> section of the Companion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-historical-recipe-collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-historical-recipe-collection/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="guide-to-historical-recipes-and-collections">Guide to historical recipes and collections&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>There are far more sources available in online library collections that
you may wish to use instead, below is a sample of sources we found
useful in Making and Knowing classes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also recommend scouring your institutional library’s holdings for
historical items related to food and recipes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sources-in-english">Sources in English&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://wellcomecollection.org/works/u3w8qbrt/items?canvas=30">Wellcome Ms. 213: A Booke of diuers
Medecines, Broothes, Salues, Waters, Syroppes and Oyntementes of which many or the
most part haue been experienced and tryed by the speciall practize of
Mrs Corlyon. Anno Domini 1606.&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-instructor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-instructor/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="historical-culinary-recipe-reconstruction">&lt;strong>Historical Culinary Recipe Reconstruction&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/culinaryreconstruction.jpg"
 alt="Culinary Reconstruction">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>Cooking is an almost universal activity – it is an art, a craft, a
science – and yet most people do it without categorizing it as such.
Cooking can provide a way for instructors to introduce hands-on
experiments and close textual analysis to their students, many of whom
will be used to following instructions from recipes and may feel more
comfortable engaging in a hands-on activity in a kitchen than a studio,
lab, or classroom. It is also very suitable for at-home assignments, or
in-class activities, as most processes can be conducted in a home or
institutional kitchen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-student/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-student/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="historical-culinary-recipe-reconstruction--student-activity-sheet">Historical Culinary Recipe Reconstruction – Student Activity Sheet&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Do the required reading and watching &lt;strong>before&lt;/strong> you start your
reconstruction. Explore and use the websites listed here to search for
comparable recipes in contemporaneous sources.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="required-readingwatchinglistening-do-this-first">Required Reading/Watching/Listening (do this first)&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Ken Albala, “Cooking as Research Methodology: Experiments in
Renaissance Cuisine,” &lt;em>Renaissance Food from Rabelais to
Shakespeare: Culinary Readings and Culinary Histories&lt;/em>, ed. Joan
Fitzpatrick (Aldershot, UK: Ashgate, 2010), pp. 73–88.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://youtu.be/pdEbMBe0aa8">Syrup of Violets and Science&lt;/a> video (ca 8 mins).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_inks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_inks/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-inks">Making Inks&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Making and Knowing Project has reconstructed inks several times, both as products and as ingredients in more complex making processes described in Ms. Fr. 640. While the manuscript is itself written in iron gall ink (the &amp;ldquo;common&amp;rdquo; black writing ink of the Renaissance), it does not include any writing ink recipes. Learning about and making writing inks can shed light on the history and materiality of texts. Because of their relatively simple ingredients and the speed and ease of their making, writing inks are an excellent hands-on activity for beginners and experts alike. The activity can be done in small groups, as a demonstration for a larger audience, or as part of a deeper personal exploration of the materials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_jasper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_jasper/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-jasper">Making Jasper&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ms. Fr. 640 contains just one entry about jasper, early in the
manuscript, on fol.10r. The entry is entitled “Counterfeit jasper,” but the author-practitioner does not mean &amp;ldquo;counterfeit&amp;rdquo; in the modern sense of being fake, fraudulent, or deceitful. Rather, he uses &amp;ldquo;counterfeit&amp;rdquo; in the early modern sense of being a portrait &amp;ndash; a faithful representation of jasper. Moreoever, as the Making and Knowing Project has come to discover, his process of making jasper, with its cumulative layering of materials one atop the other, recapitulates his understanding of how the striated rock was formed in the earth. In other words, by making jasper, the author-practitioner was attempting to extend his knowledge about natural history. For him, making became a way of knowing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-lake-pigments">Making Lake Pigments&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Making and Knowing Project has used lake pigment making as a core skill-building exercise for its students. M&amp;amp;K has often assigned lake pigment making alongside &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/">verdigris growing&lt;/a>, which were then followed up by a &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_paintingpigments/">paint making and testing&lt;/a> activity. Nevertheless, lake pigment making can be done on its own.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="learning-objectives">Learning Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The activity of making lake pigments from modernized historical recipes has several potential learning outcomes, which can include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_paintingpigments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_paintingpigments/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="making-and-testing-paints-made-by-hand-from-pigments">Making and Testing Paints Made by Hand from Pigments&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/painting-title-image.png"
 alt="hand holding paintbrush in paint on mulling plate">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>The Making and Knowing Project has used paint and test card making as a core skill-building exercise for its students. Paint making has often been a follow-up activity to &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/">lake pigment making&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/">verdigris growing&lt;/a>, but paint making can also be undertaken using commercially produced pigments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="learning-objectives">Learning Objectives&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The activity of making paint and testing out those paints on a sample card has several potential learning outcomes, which can include:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_reconstruction-template-sample/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_reconstruction-template-sample/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="reconstruction-template-sample">Reconstruction Template Sample&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>This was compiled by students during discussions of their reconstruction experience. It is shared here both as a list questions you might discuss with students and as an example of the kinds of responses that you might receive from students when they are asked to reflect on how to conduct reconstruction experiments.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="projected-outcome">Projected Outcome&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What are the goals of your reconstruction?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What historical question are you trying to answer?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_sample-hcr-discussion-document/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_sample-hcr-discussion-document/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sample">SAMPLE:&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="historical-culinary-reconstruction">Historical Culinary Reconstruction&lt;/h1>
&lt;h1 id="discussion-document">Discussion Document&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>nb. These are real, unedited student comments. This document is
shared to give you a sense of the kinds of responses this activity can
elicit. Names have been redacted.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>STUDENT A&lt;/strong>– One thing that stuck out to me throughout our recipe
reconstructions was the frustration of vague instructions - what
does “a large quantity of water” mean? What does it mean to
prepare something “as beforehand”? Many of us discussed how these
unclear instructions point to a learning based on personal
interaction with more-experienced neighbors, friends, or
superiors, and on past experience, rather than merely on textual
instruction. This learning experience isn’t unique to the early
modern period. I personally was reminded of my family’s recipes
that have been photocopied and passed down by my grandmother,
which she collected from her own mother, her old church friends,
her old neighbors, and her own experience cooking for our family.
I’ve long been frustrated by her lack of specificity - in her
bread recipe, for example, a range of yeast quantities is given,
and I always have to call my mom to ask what I should do.
Community-based learning never disappeared, but there’s no place
for it in cookbooks and published works. When did culinary
instruction start to require formality and specificity? And, more
importantly, why? My first instinct is that it may relate to
industrialization and the valorization of regularity and
uniformity. But natural ingredients and processes can’t be reduced
to uniform experience, as we all know from our experiments. This
reconstruction was a reminder that embodied knowledge is as
important as, and at times more useful than, scientific knowledge.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_stucco/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_stucco/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="making-stucco-for-molding">Making Stucco for Molding&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Making and Knowing Project has reconstructed variants of a recipe for &amp;ldquo;stucco for molding,&amp;rdquo; as described in BnF Ms. Fr. 640. This recipe uses tragacanth gum and either chalk or rye flour to produce a paste that can take on quite detailed shapes in simple molds (wood, metal, silicone) and that is very hard once dry. This activity is cheap, easy, and relatively safe to undertake with a variety of learners.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_suggestions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_suggestions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Suggestions for Additional Lesson Plans&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_supportsurfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_supportsurfaces/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="preparing-panels-canvases-and-other-supports-for-painting-gilding-and-more">Preparing Panels, Canvases, and Other Supports for Painting, Gilding, and More&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/supports-canvas-part1.png" alt="canvas-part1">
&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/supports-canvas-part2.png" alt="canvas-part2">
&lt;sup>&lt;sub>Images: Preparing a canvas for painting.&lt;/sub>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This activity teaches students how to prepare common supports, namely panels and canvases, to receive paint. The preparations outlined below ensure that any media applied to the support goes on evenly without risk of bleeding into or through that support. This activity can be undertaken as a stand-alone skill-building exercise or it can be a prelude to &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_paintingpigments/">paint making and testing&lt;/a> using &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/">hand-made lake pigments&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/">hand-grown verdigris&lt;/a>, and/or &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/azurite-assignment/">hand-levigated azurite&lt;/a>. The Making and Knowing Project has found it useful to have various prepared panels and canvases on hand for other hands-on activities and experiments, such as applying metal leaf, varnish enamels, and metalpoint, and pounced designs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_tips-for-instructors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_tips-for-instructors/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="tip-sheet-for-hands-on-teaching">Tip Sheet for Hands-on Teaching&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="skill">Skill&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Making and Knowing Project team members were almost never expert in the hands-on activities they included in courses.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Accustom yourself to not being an expert, but instead, a co-learner. Explore alongside your students&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure you try the activity before you assign it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Have students and instructor(s) work together or in groups — use an &amp;ldquo;apprenticeship&amp;rdquo; model, ideally with participants of different skill levels&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Work around a table or together at a bench so participants can watch each other&amp;rsquo;s process, and discuss and reflect together&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring in &amp;ldquo;expert practitioners&amp;rdquo; to your class to help with unfamiliar processes. We often found that the historical processes were a learning experience for expert practitioners as well. See Expert Practitioner Tonny Beentjes&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/essays/ann_334_ie_19">Tutor or Student? An Expert Maker Perspective&lt;/a> Expert practitioners may be closwer than you think — members of the local community and even your own students (ask them about their hands-on experience(s).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="teaching-scenario-building">Teaching Scenario Building&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hands-on activities are great for teaching and learning scenario building. Plan ahead and design the activity:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_varnishes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_varnishes/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="making-varnishes">Making Varnishes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Making and Knowing Project has reconstructed varnish recipes several times, both as products and as ingredients in more complex making processes described in Ms. Fr. 640. The manuscript includes several recipes for spirit varnishes, which were a new category of varnish that emerged in the sixteenth century. It also includes several recipes for oil-based varnishes, which have a longer history and are quite dangerous to reconstruct and often result in fires. Accordingly, M&amp;amp;K is only sharing protocols for making spirit varnishes. Nevertheless, making spirit varnishes raises several safety concerns and may not be suitable for all pedagogical contexts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/azurite-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/azurite-assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="azurite-grinding-washing-and-painting">Azurite: Grinding, Washing, and Painting&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2022-11-30 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A downloadable version of this assignment: [&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/azurite_assignment_downloadable_2022.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/azurite-shells.jpg?raw=true" alt="azurite in shells">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="presentations--handouts">Presentations &amp;amp; Handouts&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/fa22_skillbuilding-azurite-presentation-full.pdf">Presentation: Preparing and Painting Blue Pigments in the Renaissance&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>See also a &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/fa22_skillbuilding-azurite-presentation-short.pdf">short version of this presentation focused on azurite&lt;/a> (with additional information on Ms. Fr. 640)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/azurite_assignment_handout_2022.pdf">Student Handout&lt;/a> (to have while doing the hands-on reconstruction)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/fa22_skillbuilding-azurite-presentation-full.pdf">&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/preparing-painting-blue.png" alt="Preparing and Painting Blue Pigment in the Renaissance"/>&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding-student-activity-sheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding-student-activity-sheet/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="class-activity-making-bread-and-making-molds-from-bread">Class Activity: Making Bread and Making Molds from Bread&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="objectives">Objectives&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>explore historical breadmaking recipes and techniques&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>learn to bake bread&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>produce loaves of bread to use as molds&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This activity has two parts&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Part 1 (at home before class): learn to bake bread and produce loaves to use as molds for a small object&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Part 2 (in class): pour wax (and/or sulfur) into your molds, then unmold&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="source-text">Source text&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are two entries on breadmolding on &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/140v/f/140v/tl">&lt;u>fol. 140v&lt;/u>.&lt;/a>
Another on &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/156r/f/156r/tl">&lt;u>fol.156r&lt;/u>&lt;/a> mentions breadmolding as an alternative process for “Molding promptly.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding_resources-for-the-instructor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding_resources-for-the-instructor/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bread-making-molding-and-casting-for-the-instructor">Bread Making, Molding, and Casting (for the Instructor)&lt;/h1>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/breadmolding-kneading.jpg"
 alt="Kneading Bread">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The sixteenth-century artisanal/technical manual, BnF Ms. Fr. 640, contains
hundreds of entries that describe making processes and techniques from
the Renaissance. These include instructions for and observations about
painting, gilding, arms and armor production, plant cultivation, and
making molds and metal casts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ms. Fr. 640 contains three mentions of bread as a material that can be
used to take an impression of another object quickly and neatly. This impression
can be used as a mold into which sulfur or wax is cast. It is an example
of the kind of intermediate process that artists must have relied on
in the sixteenth century, akin to making a 3D printed prototype in resin
before casting in gold for a modern jeweler, but for which very little historical evidence survives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/burnsalve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/burnsalve/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="activity-reconstruction-of-a-16th-century-burn-salve-recipe">Activity: Reconstruction of a 16th-Century Burn Salve Recipe&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The study of historical recipes or &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rdquo; instructions can be a powerful tool to engage with the past and to learn about daily life in a different, more tangible way than traditional textual sources. Historical reconstruction &amp;ndash; attempting to follow or replicate the recipe &amp;ndash; can bring the past to life and provide new perspectives for experts and students alike.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The activity sheet and resources below are intended to invite you to undertake a hands-on historical reconstruction yourself, or to provide you with what you will need to bring this activity into your classroom, studio, or even kitchen. It is recommended that the exercise be undertaken by students in middle (or secondary) school and older, due to the heating of oil and beeswax.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dyeing-with-natural-colorants-teaching-resources-activity-sheets-and-dye-samples">Dyeing with Natural Colorants: Teaching Resources, Activity Sheets, and Dye Samples&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Resources for dyeing textiles with natural colorants (including cochineal, madder, weld, and redwoods) following historical dye recipes. Recipes and procedure adapted from Jo Kirby et al, &lt;em>Natural Colorants for Dyeing and Lake Pigments: Practical Recipes and their Historical Sources&lt;/em> (London: Archetype, 2014)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/2023_dyes_cochineal-history-chem-prep.pdf">Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation&lt;/a> - an overview of historical natural colorants and dyes, details about common red colorants, a deep-dive into the history of cochineal insects as a dye and pigment source, the preparation of mordant dyes, and explanation of the chemistry of these natural colorants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/rosenkranz_2018_dyes_cochineal-step-by-step.pdf">Presentation: Dyeing: Step-by-Step Instructions&lt;/a> with information about sourcing materials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/sp23_handout_dyeing-textiles_general-process.pdf">Handout: One-page Instruction Sheet for Mordant and Dye Process&lt;/a> - procedure and instructions that can be adapted for any number of mordants and dye sources&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/rosenkranz_2018_dyes_handout_dyeing-with-cochineal.pdf">Activity Sheet: Mordant Dyeing with Cochineal&lt;/a> - instructions for mordanting textiles with alum and dyeing with cochineal (and/or cochineal with potash as an additive)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/activitysheet_mordants-dyes-recipes-calculator.pdf">Activity Sheet: Calculating ratios and amounts of dyestuffs, mordants, and textiles for dyeing&lt;/a> - created as part of a reconstruction exchange workshop with &lt;a href="http://refashioningrenaissance.eu/">Refashioning the Renaissance&lt;/a> in March 2019 on dyes (presentation above). Application of parts of the template provided below&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/activity-sheets/rosenkranz_2019_dyes_TEMPLATE-AND-RECIPES_dye-experiments.xlsx">Template and recipes: natural dyes&lt;/a> - a spreadsheet pre-populated with recipes for natural colorants, information about sourcing materials, as well as templates and examples for calculating ingredient amounts based on the amount of textile to be dyed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/3oVnsawjQkq3JNCX7">Pictures: dye sample book (Naomi Rosenkranz)&lt;/a> - an incomplete sample of various dye experiments from the Making and Knowing Lab (and home kitchens!) with different combinations of textiles, natural colorants, mordants, and additives.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-cochineal_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-cochineal_assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dyeing-textiles-with-cochineal-a-historical-reconstruction">Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal: A Historical Reconstruction&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2023-03-30 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A downloadable version of this assignment: [&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/dyes-cochineal_assignment_downloadable_2023.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/cochineal-dyed-textiles-mix.JPG?raw=true" alt="dyes-cochineal_header">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="dyes-and-natural-colorants">Dyes and natural colorants&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are not already familiar with historical dyes and natural colorants, refer to &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/2023_dyes_cochineal-history-chem-prep.pdf">Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation&lt;/a> for more complete information and further explanation of natural colorants and dyeing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/2023_dyes_cochineal-history-chem-prep.pdf">&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/cochineal-dye-presentation-slide.JPG" alt="Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/introduction-fieldnotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/introduction-fieldnotes/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction-to-field-notes">Introduction to Field Notes&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In the early days of what would become the Making and Knowing Project,
Founding Director Pamela Smith came to a realization: in order to
remember and then write about her experiences in lifecasting, she would
have to take meticulous notes. Amidst the cacophony of sounds, sights,
and smells in the blacksmith&amp;rsquo;s workshop, her experimentations passed in
a blur. It was only through detailed notes that she could keep
everything straight. As she organized her jottings each night, she began
to see these notes as a space for wider reflection, not just
documentation of minute processes and results. This realization was
carried over into the Project’s Laboratory Seminar. As students
undertook their own multi-week historical reconstruction research, field
notes became a central tool in chronicling not just the product, but the
processes of making and knowing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/painting-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/painting-assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-paints-from-pigments-and-painting-them-out">Making Paints from Pigments and Painting Them Out&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2024-07-29 by PHS&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A downloadable version of this assignment: [&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/painting_assignment_downloadable_2021.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/painting-header.png?raw=true" alt="painting-header">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="paint--pigment--binding-media">Paint = Pigment + Binding Media&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Refer to &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/introduction-paints-pigments_njr_2021.pdf">Presentation: Introduction to Pigments &amp;amp; Paints&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/painting-pigment-binding-media.png" alt="painting-pigment-binding-media">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overview-of-activity">Overview of Activity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Much more detailed information and resources are provided below in this document. To help get you started, this is an overview of the hands-on work and preparation you will do:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-cochineal-lake_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-cochineal-lake_assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-lake-pigment-from-cochineal-a-historical-reconstruction">MAKING LAKE PIGMENT FROM COCHINEAL: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2021-09-29 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A downloadable version of this assignment: [&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/pigment-cochineal-lake_assignment_downloadable_2023.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/pigment-cochineal_header.png?raw=true" alt="pigment-cochineal_header">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lake-pigments-and-natural-colorants">Lake pigments and natural colorants&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are not already familiar with historical pigments and natural colorants, refer to &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/presentation_sp23_rosenkranz_naomi_lakes_cochineal-history-chem-prep.pdf">Presentation: Cochineal Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation&lt;/a> for more complete information and further explanation of natural colorants and lake pigments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See also &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/introduction-paints-pigments_njr_2021.pdf">Presentation: Introduction to Pigments &amp;amp; Paints&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-madder-lake_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-madder-lake_assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-lake-pigment-with-madder-a-historical-reconstruction">MAKING LAKE PIGMENT WITH MADDER: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2023-09-29 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you are not already familiar with historical pigments and natural colorants, refer to &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/presentation_sp23_rosenkranz_naomi_lakes_madder-history-chem-prep.pdf">&lt;u>Presentation: Madder Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation&lt;/u>&lt;/a> for more complete information and further explanation of natural colorants and lake pigments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/presentation_sp23_rosenkranz_naomi_lakes_madder-history-chem-prep.pdf">&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/madder-lake-presentation.jpg?raw=true" alt="Presentation: Madder Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Refer also to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/introduction-paints-pigments_njr_2021.pdf">Presentation: Introduction to Pigments &amp;amp; Paints&lt;/a> - a general introduction to colorants&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp22_fld_rosenkranz_naomi_madder-lake-trio/">Making Pigment from Madder: a Trio of Recipes&lt;/a> - helpful step-by-step fieldnotes for all three madder pigment recipes described below&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="lake-pigments">Lake Pigments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Lake pigments are a type of pigment prepared from organic natural colorants: plant and animal sources. As most organic natural colorants are soluble, they cannot be mixed directly with a binding medium and therefore cannot be used as a pigment. These colorants must therefore be extracted and then made insoluble in order to use them as pigments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt-2/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="secrets-of-craft-and-nature-reconnaissance-directed-scavenger-hunt">&lt;em>Secrets of Craft and Nature&lt;/em> Reconnaissance (Directed Scavenger Hunt)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>A downloadable version of this assignment: [&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/scavenger-hunt-recon_downloadable_2022.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BnF Ms. Fr. 640 has 170 folios (340 pages) with over 900 entries on metalworking, casting, painting, medicine, and sleight of hand tricks. This is an exercise with two activities to help become familiar with the online Edition and Translation of Ms. Fr. 640: &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org">&lt;em>Secrets of Craft and Nature&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you start, watch this &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/998222542">video&lt;/a> for tips on navigating through &lt;em>Secrets of Craft and Nature&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt_secrets-of-craft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt_secrets-of-craft/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="scavenger-hunt-get-to-know-secrets-of-craft-and-nature">Scavenger Hunt: Get to know &lt;em>Secrets of Craft and Nature&lt;/em>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Browse&lt;/strong> the online Edition of Ms. Fr. 640: &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org">&lt;em>Secrets of Craft and Nature&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Explore&lt;/strong> each menu item.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Watch&lt;/strong> this &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/998222542">video&lt;/a> for tips on navigating through &lt;em>Secrets of Craft and Nature&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Complete&lt;/strong> the &lt;strong>scavenger hunt&lt;/strong> of the Edition&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Pick three of the following terms (or another term of your choosing), and use the search bar to search the manuscript: 
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;mercury,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;bread,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;rat,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;dog,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;cuttlefish,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;saliva,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;garlic,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;blood,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;rosemary,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;milk,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;horse,”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“earwax”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Browse the results and select &lt;strong>one&lt;/strong> of the occurrences in the manuscript that you find interesting. Please note the page number (e.g., fol. 76v) and URL (e.g., &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/76v/f/76v/tl">https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/76v/f/76v/tl&lt;/a>) from which you viewed the recipe or entry containing the term. &lt;strong>Keep notes for discussion.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What is the recipe for? Is it a recipe at all? If not, how would you characterize it? How is the relevant object/material/animal used in the recipe? Was this use or the material surprising to you? How does this manuscript entry relate to the study of material culture, art history, or the history of science? Could you reconstruct this object/material?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Is there an essay associated with this entry in the manuscript (click on the beaker icon on the right of the entry)? Does it provide new insights or answer your questions about this recipe?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="teaching-resources">Teaching Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For an account of how the Making and Knowing Project created the edition through courses and workshops:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp22_fld_rosenkranz_naomi_madder-lake-trio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp22_fld_rosenkranz_naomi_madder-lake-trio/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-lake-pigment-with-madder-a-historical-reconstruction">MAKING LAKE PIGMENT WITH MADDER: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2022-01-29 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As summarized in &lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-madder-lake_assignment/">Activity Sheet: Making Lake Pigment with Madder&lt;/a>, there are three historical recipe types for making lake pigment from madder. In Spring 2022, Naomi Rosenkranz and Charlotte Atkins undertook all three versions at once to make direct comparisons between them. Their field notes, working from the activity sheet, are presented below with extensive images of the process. They show the Making and Knowing Project&amp;rsquo;s method for reconstruction of the process of lake pigment making from madder roots in the M&amp;amp;K lab.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp23_dyes_tamu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp23_dyes_tamu/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bioart-workshop-dyeing-with-cochineal-bugs">BioArt Workshop: Dyeing with Cochineal Bugs&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2023-03-24 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pvfa.tamu.edu/news/2023/03/20/bio-art-workshops-to-show-creative-process-using-cochineal-insects-bacteria/">Texas A&amp;amp;M PVFA/BIOL BioArt Workshop&lt;/a>&lt;br/>
March 21–24, 2023&lt;br/>
Organized by Tianna Uchacz with Donna Janes and Naomi Rosenkranz&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cochineal-dye-history-chemistry-and-preparation">Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/sp23_tamu-dyes-coverpage.jpg?raw=true" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/2023_dyes_cochineal-history-chem-prep_TAMU-compressed.pdf">Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overview-of-workshop-plans">Overview of Workshop Plans&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/tamu_cochineal-step-by-step.jpg?raw=true" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/2023_dyes_step-by-step-process_TAM.pdf">Dyeing with Cochineal: Workshop Plan and Step-by-Step Instructions&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="handouts">Handouts&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/sp23_handout_dyeing-textiles_general-process.pdf">Dyeing Instructions - General Process for Mordanting and Dyeing Textiles&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/sp23_printout_samples-amounts.pdf">Summary of Dye Samples and Measurements&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/sp23_printout_recipe-example-piemontese.pdf">Recipe Example: &lt;em>De&amp;rsquo; secreti del reverendo signore Alessio Piemontese&lt;/em> (1558)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="summary-of-materials-and-samples">Summary of Materials and Samples&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">Name&lt;/th>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">Mordant&lt;/th>
 &lt;th style="text-align: center">Dye&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">NC&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">None&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Cochineal&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">NCP&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">None&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Cochineal + potash&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">AC&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Alum&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Cochineal&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">ACP&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Alum&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Cochineal + potash&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">IC&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Iron sulphate&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Cochineal&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">CC&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Copper sulphate&lt;/td>
 &lt;td style="text-align: center">Cochineal&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/sp23_tamu-dyes_textiles.jpg?raw=true" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco-assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="stucco-for-molding-reconstruction">STUCCO FOR MOLDING RECONSTRUCTION&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>HIST GR8906: Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World | Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2021-09-24 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/stucco-header.jpg?raw=true" alt="stucco-header">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A downloadable version of this assignment: [&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/stucco_assignment_downloadable_2021.pdf">&lt;strong>PDF&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>NOTE TO INSTRUCTORS:&lt;/strong> Rather than providing the full instructions, one may want to provide students only with the original recipe and the materials, allowing them to interpret the entry for themselves. A &amp;ldquo;student handout&amp;rdquo; is available:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco_assignment_student-handout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco_assignment_student-handout/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="stucco-for-molding-reconstruction---student-handout">STUCCO FOR MOLDING RECONSTRUCTION - STUDENT HANDOUT&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>HIST GR8906: Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World | Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2021-09-24 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="ephemeral-art-in-bnf-ms-fr-640">Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The 16th-century artisanal/technical manual, BnF Ms. Fr. 640, contains hundreds of entries that describe making processes and techniques from the Renaissance. These include instructions for and observations about painting, gilding, arms and armor production, plant cultivation, and making molds and metal casts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su17_rosenkranz_azurite-preparation-cambridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su17_rosenkranz_azurite-preparation-cambridge/</guid><description>&lt;p>June 5, 2017&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Azurite crushing and washing session&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Led by Spike Bucklow, Fitzwilliam studio room, Cambridge University&lt;br>
Workshop organized by the Ingenuity Project (Alex Marr) with the Making Visible Project (Sachiko Kusukawa) and the curatorial team of the Fitzwilliam Museum’s “&lt;a href="http://www.fitzmuseum.cam.ac.uk/madonnasandmiracles">&lt;u>Madonnas and Miracles&lt;/u>&lt;/a>” exhibit (March - June 2017)&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Participants:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>ERC group “Ingenuity” (Alex Marr, Richard, Raf, Jose)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Making Visible Project” (Sachiko Kusukawa, Katie, Seitske)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Madonnas and Miracles” exhibition team at the Fitzwilliam Museum (Maya, Irena)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“Making and Knowing Project (Pamela, Tianna, Naomi)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Notes by NJR (Naomi Rosenkranz)&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dyeing-with-onion-skins">Dyeing with Onion Skins&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Annika Cunningham, summer and fall 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My name is Annika Cunningham, and I am a high schooler in Boston. I have
been weaving, knitting, and crocheting for over a decade, and also enjoy
exploring the scientific methods behind these crafts. I wanted to
experiment with dye-making techniques using more affordable and
accessible materials, like onion skins!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onions originated in Asia and the Middle East, but the exact period and
geographic origin are uncertain. Turkish artisans in the mid-1400s
started using onion skins to dye carpets and rugs. Additionally, many
artisans still use these methods to create authentic rugs today. Natural
Dyes were also used by early Navajo artisans, who are known for their
woven rugs and blankets. Many started using natural dyes in the 1700s
and, in Navajo weaver Mable Burnside-Myer’s Dye chart, she shows the use
of onion skins in her work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/varnish-sourcing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/varnish-sourcing/</guid><description>&lt;p>varnish sourcing&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="growing-verdigris">&amp;ldquo;GROWING&amp;rdquo; VERDIGRIS&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>Last updated 2021-08-19 by NJR&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A downloadable version of this assignment: [&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/verdigris_assignment_downloadable_2021.pdf">PDF&lt;/a>]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/verdigris-header.png?raw=true" alt="verdigris-header">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Safety Note: Nitrile/latex gloves must be worn when handling verdigris. Do not touch your mouth or bare skin. Do not scrape or grind the verdigris on food preparation surfaces.&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Verdigris is a blue-green pigment prepared by exposing copper to acetic acid (vinegar), forming a basic copper acetate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/digital/2024-data-management-plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/digital/2024-data-management-plan/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-making-and-knowing-project">The Making and Knowing Project&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Last updated 2023 by NJR and THC
The Making and Knowing Project&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="data-management-plan">Data Management Plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Data management is a responsibility upheld by all participants of the
the Making and Knowing Project and overseen by the Project Director, Assistant Director, and Digital Lead. The methodologies, decisions, and data management strategies
described below have been developed by the Making and Knowing Project in
the creation of &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org">&lt;em>&lt;u>Secrets of Craft and Nature in Renaissance France.
A Digital Critical Edition of BnF Ms. Fr.
640&lt;/u>&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. These principles,
influenced by the culture of “&lt;a href="https://go-dh.github.io/mincomp/">&lt;u>minimal
computing&lt;/u>&lt;/a>” at Columbia
University, guide all content creation and digital development. All
decisions and modes of work are informed by two guiding principles: to
generate and preserve all project data in sustainable and open formats
while best facilitating the multifaceted collaborative research process;
and to ensure commitment to open access and open source standards
wherever possible. Data management will comply with Columbia policies
for &lt;a href="http://research.columbia.edu/ReaDI-Program">&lt;u>Research and Data
Integrity&lt;/u>&lt;/a> as well as
guidelines and standards for the social sciences and humanities,
including the &lt;a href="https://sca.jiscinvolve.org/wp/files/2009/10/sca_bp_projects_scholarly_content_sep09_v1-02.pdf">&lt;em>&lt;u>Sustaining Digital Resources: A Briefing Paper for
Leaders of Projects with Scholarly
Content&lt;/u>&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
and the &lt;a href="https://sites.haa.pitt.edu/sustainabilityroadmap/">&lt;em>&lt;u>Socio-Technical Sustainability
Roadmap&lt;/u>&lt;/em>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/bibliography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/bibliography/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bibliography-for-hands-on-teaching-and-learning">Bibliography for Hands-On Teaching and Learning&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Almevik, Gunnar, Camilla Groth, and Tina Westerlund. Explorations in Craft Sciences. 2-18, 2022. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.21524/kriterium.40">https://doi.org/10.21524/kriterium.40&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beentjes, Tonny, and Pamela H. Smith. “Sixteenth-century life-casting techniques: experimental reconstructions based on a preserved manuscript.” In The Renaissance Workshop, edited by David Saunders, Marika Spring and Andrew Meek. London: Archetype Publications Ltd, 2013, 144-51.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bilak, Donna. “Out of the Ivy and into the Arctic: Imitation Coral Reconstruction in Cross-Cultural Contexts.” Berichte Zur Wissenschaftsgeschichte 43, no. 3 (2020): 341–66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/bewi.202000010">https://doi.org/10.1002/bewi.202000010&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/uchacz-course-reflection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/uchacz-course-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="teaching-reflections-and-tips-from-texas-am---tianna-uchacz">Teaching Reflections and Tips from Texas A&amp;amp;M - Tianna Uchacz&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Tianna Uchacz served as Postdoctoral Scholar of the Making and Knowing Project 2016-2020, co-instructing M&amp;amp;K courses, developing hands-on activities, and fostering collaborations between diverse scholars, students, and practitioners. Since 2020, Tianna Uchacz is Assistant Professor of Art History at Texas A&amp;amp;M University. She has adapted existing courses to incorporate hands-on work and developed new classes with a dedicated focus on materials and the exploration of artistic proccess. Her notes and reflections are below, including ideas and logistics for scaling up activities and new instructional materials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_alberts_naomi_final-project_ph-lesson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_alberts_naomi_final-project_ph-lesson/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="instructor-assignment-sheet-ms-fr-640-fol-43v-varied-and-transmuted-wine">Instructor Assignment Sheet: Ms. Fr. 640 fol. 43v, “Varied and Transmuted Wine”&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>by Naomi Alberts, Fall 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="objective">Objective:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Introducing and explaining concepts related to pH to students. pH
testing refers to determining how acidic or basic a water-based solution
is. Additionally, getting students to think about the physical property
of color and what a change in color can tell an observer. Finally,
making historical connections between pre-Scientific Revolution and
current/modern scientific views, while also exploring the “boundaries
and relationship between seventeenth-century art and science.”
&lt;sup>1&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_atkins-joyce-farley_charlotte-siobhan_pranks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_atkins-joyce-farley_charlotte-siobhan_pranks/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-exploration-of-humor-in-ms-fr-640">An Exploration of Humor in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Charlotte Atkins and Siobhan Joyce-Farley, Fall 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BFK71x0bvuE" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>When we decided to recreate and record riddles from Ms. Fr. 640 for our
final project, our major interests were exploring accessible entry
points into the manuscript and thinking about how modes of entertainment
have and haven’t evolved across location and history. We thought that
riddles and practical jokes would be easy to recreate authentically, and
we assumed that their societal function would have stayed relatively
fixed across time. Once we actually began to research and film the
riddles, however, we realized our initial assumptions weren’t totally
correct.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_coutavas_allie_final-project-reds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_coutavas_allie_final-project-reds/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-color-red-in-ms-fr-640">The Color Red in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Alexandra Coutavas&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fall 2021, Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bibliothèque nationale de France Ms. Fr. 640 is a late sixteenth-century
manuscript containing instructions, recipes, and practical notes on a
variety of subjects pertaining to crafts. As a text dealing with art
making and materials, the names of colors and pigments appear frequently
throughout. Using Carl Garris’ “What is &lt;em>Azur&lt;/em> in Ms. Fr. 640?” and
other published essays of the digital critical edition as models, this
paper investigates words related to ‘red’ in the manuscript, both as the
color &lt;em>rouge&lt;/em> and as red pigments and materials including lake,
vermilion, cinnabar, and rosette.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Although some color and pigment
words were used indiscriminately and interchangeably at the time, the
aim here is to track usages across the manuscript to see if certain
formulations appear in certain contexts. The first stage of this
research analyzes the entries in the manuscript to record the
author-practitioner’s language, and the second stage attempts to
identify patterns or meaning in use of words.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_ghoneima_hana_final-project-oral-culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_ghoneima_hana_final-project-oral-culture/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="oral-culture-in-ms-fr-640">Oral Culture in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hana Ghoneima&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Making and Knowing Project, Fall 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BnF Ms. Fr. 640 stands at the intersection of a pivotal moment in
history, in which craftspeople who were previously illiterate began
recording their procedures and trade in writing.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Within this context,
Ms. Fr. 640 is an illuminating document not only for its content on
craft techniques, but for the historical milestones and trends it
embodies. One of those is oral culture, and its intersection with the
written one. Oral culture is defined as a form of communication in which
knowledge is transmitted orally from one person to another. According to
the historian Jan Vansina, within oral culture &amp;ldquo;there must be
transmission by word of mouth over at least a generation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>
Importantly, oral culture can be interpreted as “Any situation in which
people speak generates messages, some of which may be repeated and hence
start a process of transmission,” and it includes both the process of
oral transmission itself as well as its products.&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Similarly, oral
culture can also be thought of as “a reconstruction of the past from
oral sources…which will throw light on the particular aspect of social
life under study.”&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> As such, oral culture is understood as the shared
transmission of vernacular experience, and is an important tool for the
study of historical eras in which masses were largely illiterate and
access to written work limited.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_jacobson_beah_final-project-know/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_jacobson_beah_final-project-know/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="textual-analysis-of-instances-of-to-know-in-ms-fr-640">Textual Analysis of Instances of “To Know” in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Beah Jacobson, Fall 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On folio &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/125r/f/125r/tcn">&lt;u>125r of BnF Ms. Fr.
640&lt;/u>&lt;/a>,
the phrase “a sçavoir” appears circled and set off from a stream of
surrounding marginal text on plaster; its placement suggests that it may
accompany the folio’s “Scimitars” entry. Combined with an auxiliary “a,”
this phrase is somewhat more enigmatic than the straightforward English
infinitive “to know,” as translated in the &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/">&lt;u>Digital Critical
Edition&lt;/u>&lt;/a> of the Making &amp;amp; Knowing
Project. Rather, we might take it as a gerund or part of a verbal phrase
– something closer to the procedural sense of “for knowing” than “to
know.” Did this note in fact refer to the scimitar recipe? If so, what
made that particular recipe so worth knowing for the manuscript’s
author-practitioner? Does the phrase indicate familiarity with or the
need to learn a particular knowledge-set? And what, for the
author-practitioner, is the relationship between scimitar-making and
knowledge-making?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_lin-sundar_danli-anusha_final-project_regimens-remedies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_lin-sundar_danli-anusha_final-project_regimens-remedies/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="regimens-recipes-and-remedies-understanding-the-cosmetic-in-early-modern-europe">Regimens, Recipes, and Remedies: Understanding the “Cosmetic” in Early Modern Europe&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Danli Lin and Anusha Sundar&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fall 2021, Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A Google search of the word “cosmetic” yields many meanings, including
anything related to beautification, correcting defects, decorating, and
clearing one’s complexion. We are also immediately reminded of beauty
models, or the scores of beauty products that line the aisles of
supermarkets. There is also the endless barrage of advertisements
featuring glistening hair, glowing skin, and miraculously spot-free
skin! Yet, there is a longer history to the world of cosmetics that is
not limited to the idea of beauty, just as scholars have pointed to how
notions of beauty are historically contingent on regions, communities,
gender, and social strata. This essay discusses how ideas about
cosmetics were closely aligned to medicinal and therapeutic uses in
early modern Europe. This will help us understand the multiplicity of
meanings that these historical understandings and quotidian uses
produced.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_steinman_charlie_final-project-ms262/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_steinman_charlie_final-project-ms262/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="transcribing-translating-and-encoding-ms-gen-262-sefer-refuos-u-segulos--book-of-remedies-and-incantations">Transcribing, Translating, and Encoding MS Gen, 262: &lt;em>Sefer Refu&amp;rsquo;os u-Segulos / Book of Remedies and Incantations&lt;/em>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Charlie Steinman
Fall 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-ms">About the MS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://archive.org/details/ldpd_11728201_000">&lt;u>Columbia MS Gen.
262&lt;/u>&lt;/a> is a collection
of recipes and other instructional texts written by a Yiddish-speaking,
Jewish practitioner in Northern Italy around 1470. The bulk of the
manuscript is in a dialect of Old Western Yiddish, bearing witness to
the increasing presence of Jews from the German-speaking lands in Italy.
Nonetheless, it is a decidedly multilingual document. Most recipes not
written in Yiddish are written in Hebrew, although there is one
incantation in Ladino. The Yiddish and Hebrew bleed freely into one
another, and the manuscript is peppered with little bits of the local
Italian vernacular, mostly for naming/glossing plants and other objects.
There are also some magical words in Latin and Aramaic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_weisgall_benjamin_final-project-architecture-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_weisgall_benjamin_final-project-architecture-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-making-and-meaning-of-intermediates-workshop-and-syllabus-for-students-of-architecture">The Making and Meaning of Intermediates: Workshop and Syllabus for Students of Architecture&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Benjamin Weisgall&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/media-weisgall/image1.png" alt="IMAGE">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Screen capture from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PHgEcPmCPUA&amp;amp;t=14s">&lt;u>“How was it made? Plaster
cast”&lt;/u>&lt;/a> by the V&amp;amp;A
Museum&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following six-week unit is designed for students of art and
architecture and others who are already comfortable in the workshop
(&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/166r">&lt;em>&lt;u>la
boutique&lt;/u>&lt;/em>&lt;/a>)
but may be less familiar with the uses and pleasures of historical study
(&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/39v">&lt;em>&lt;u>quelque
histoire&lt;/u>&lt;/em>&lt;/a>).
Using the digital critical edition of Ms. Fr. 640, student-participants
will follow the author-practitioner and his interlocutors into an
intensive study of early modern molding and casting. This unit adopts
the M&amp;amp;K Project’s dual pedagogical approach of conceptual articulation
alongside material fabrication, with the ultimate goal of developing
research skills in the history of techniques.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Student-participants
will not only learn how to work through actual historical “recipes” for
&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/139v/f/139v/tl">&lt;u>patternmaking&lt;/u>&lt;/a>
and
&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/83v/f/83v/tl">&lt;u>moldmaking&lt;/u>&lt;/a>,
but they will also have the opportunity to think creatively about those
techniques in the range of possibilities that they afford. In order to
achieve this middle position between historical work and artistic work,
the unit takes as its theme the variety of intermediary objects that are
inherent to any process of casting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_zayas-waters_elliot-mac_final-project-soundscape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/fa21_zayas-waters_elliot-mac_final-project-soundscape/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-soundscape-of-process-an-audio-recreation-of-lifecasting-in-the-workshop">The Soundscape of Process: An Audio Recreation of Lifecasting in the Workshop&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Elliot Zayas and Mac Waters, Fall 2021&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the introduction to his history of audio reproduction technologies,
Jonathan Sterne outlines the supposed supremacy of visual concerns in
many of the primary cultural academic disciplines. From the obsession
with the “gaze” to the primacy of the visual object, visual cultures
have dominated scholarship for centuries. Musicologist Kate Galloway
expands this observation to the recent developments of the digital
humanities, noting that “the digital humanities continues to be
astonishingly silent” (Galloway, 47), prioritizing visual and literary
scholarship. Over the past decade or so, Galloway notes that “Soundwork”
has slowly begun to creep into digital humanities fields not necessarily
in the form of sound or music-based scholarship, but in the presence of
actual sound &lt;em>objects&lt;/em> that are created using recording and sound
analysis technologies. These objects are not scholarship that is meant
to be read in an academic journal, but rather experienced by listeners
interactively—such objects are meant to be heard. The primary
pedagogical point of these objects, Galloway writes, is to aid in
holistic digital storytelling. By increasing the level of sensory
experience in historical reconstructions, Soundwork can help modern
scholars engage with public audiences through multisensory narratives,
providing unique insight into the sonic experiences of historical
situations, environments, and events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_arocho_alejandra_herodotus-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_arocho_alejandra_herodotus-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="herodotus-workshop-a-core-curriculum-pathway-into-ms-fr-640-and-its-author-practitioner">Herodotus’ ‘Workshop’: A Core (Curriculum) Pathway into Ms. Fr. 640 and its Author-Practitioner&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Alejandra Quintana Arocho&lt;br/>
Professor Pamela Smith | Naomi Rosenkranz | Caroline Surman&lt;br/>
Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-on History&lt;br/>
10 May 2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This project is directed toward Columbia College and General Studies students who have taken the course &amp;ldquo;Literature Humanities&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href="https://www.college.columbia.edu/core-curriculum/classes/literature-humanities">Lit Hum&lt;/a>) as part of &lt;a href="https://www.college.columbia.edu/core/core">Columbia&amp;rsquo;s Core Curriculum&lt;/a> and want to see how an author/artisan from Renaissance Toulouse participates in their ongoing literary/scholarly conversations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_bergen-sabet_jamie-sofia_final-project_grotto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_bergen-sabet_jamie-sofia_final-project_grotto/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jamie Bergen and Sofia Sabet&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spring 2022, GU4962: Hands-on History&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="creating-a-modern-reconstruction-of-a-miniature-grotto">Creating a “Modern” Reconstruction of a Miniature Grotto&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Grottos imitate a spring, often located in a cave-like structure, and
usually contain fountains, sculpture, and imitation flora and fauna.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/media-bergen-sabet/image23.jpg" alt="IMAGE">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Engraving of a grotto in the gardens of Hortus Palatinus, Heidelberg, from Salomon de Caus’ Hortus Palatinus. Engraving done by Matthieu Marian’s (1620), &lt;a href="https://digi.ub.uni-heidelberg.de/diglit/caus1620/0034/image,info,thumbs">&lt;u>https://digi.ub.uni-heidelberg.de/diglit/caus1620/0034/image,info,thumbs&lt;/u>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In &lt;em>L&amp;rsquo;Idea della Architettura Universale&lt;/em> (&lt;em>The Idea of a Universal
Architecture&lt;/em>), published in 1615, Italian architect Vincenzo Scamozzi
described “grotto porticos” that were decorated with “pebbles [and]
tuff and other materials petrified in various shapes of nature…and then
decorated here and there with niches, with statues of stone and sometime
of metal.”&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> He continues that the grotto porticos’ “ornaments shall be
fountains, niches, and tableaus with statues, inscriptions, and such
things.” He notes that “the Ancients would [decorate them with]
extravagant and ridiculous paintings… And because such paintings were
found in some places [resembling] caves, for this they call them
&lt;em>grottesche&lt;/em>.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_donald_maia_final-project_cuttlebone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_donald_maia_final-project_cuttlebone/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="cuttlefish-in-and-around-ms-fr-640">Cuttlefish in and around Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Maia Donald&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Spring 2022&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cuttlebone, the hard interior shell of the cuttlefish, has a long history of human use. While today it is primarily consumed as a calcium
supplement by pet birds and reptiles, cuttlebone was long ago used as a
polishing powder, casting material, and carving medium. Both Aristotle
and Pliny offer detailed examinations of cuttlefish in their more general overview of cephalopods.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Its near continuous use in the arts,
especially in casting, indicates that cuttlebone has historically been
an abundant material. Paradoxically, for such a widely used material,
there is little reference to its procurement and trade either in
historical sources or secondary literature.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_gardner_schuyler_final-project-sieves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_gardner_schuyler_final-project-sieves/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="sieves-in-ms-fr-640">Sieves in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Schuyler Gardner&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spring 2022, GU4962: Hands-on History&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In early modern Europe, the line between tools used in workshops and in
kitchens was blurred. Tools that crossed these spaces can reveal how
people, particularly women, could negotiate their identities within
different early modern spaces. In Ms. Fr. 640, there is a distinct
interest in tools that rest at this intersection. Whether through the
illustrations of furnaces (&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/6v">&lt;u>fol.
6v&lt;/u>&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/16r">&lt;u>fol.16r&lt;/u>&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/48r">&lt;u>fol.48r&lt;/u>&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/100v">&lt;u>fol.
100v&lt;/u>&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/101r">&lt;u>fol.
101r&lt;/u>&lt;/a>) or the
emphasis on which specific pots are to be employed in particular
processes (such as a “leaded pot” on &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/3r/tl">&lt;u>fol.
3r&lt;/u>&lt;/a> or “a
varnished earthenware pot” on &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/48v/tl">&lt;u>fol.
48v&lt;/u>&lt;/a>), the
author-practitioner displays both a knowledge of and interest in how
tools traditionally marked as belonging within the kitchen were used
more broadly. One tool, the sieve, seems to receive particular attention
from the author-practitioner. For example, “Horsehair sieves” (&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/search/folio/44v/tl?q=sieve">&lt;u>fol.
44v&lt;/u>&lt;/a>)
provides a very detailed description of the process of creating and
trading sieves:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_lang_theodora_counterproofing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_lang_theodora_counterproofing/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="counterproofing-reproduction-and-theft-in-early-modern-print-culture">Counterproofing: Reproduction and Theft in Early Modern Print Culture&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Theodora Bocanegra Lang&lt;br/>
Spring 2022&lt;br/>
Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In an entry of BnF Ms. Fr. 640 entitled “Counterproofing” (&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/51r/f/51r/tl">&lt;u>folio
51r&lt;/u>&lt;/a>, the
author-practitioner provides the reader with instructions on how to copy
a print using a method of the same name that entails wetting the print
and pressing it onto a fresh piece of paper in an attempt to dampen the
ink and ultimately transfer the image. Part of the author-practitioner&amp;rsquo;s
recommended process involves burnishing the back of the page
with a tooth or glass, which can leave indentations or marks on the
paper. In this entry there is a particularly curious sentence: “And if you want
this not to be known, if by chance, you borrowed the piece, moisten the
paper, and the polishing that the burnisher has made on the back, which
shows what has been done, will not be known.” Not only is the
author-practitioner sharing how to counterproof, he is teaching
something potentially nefarious: how to steal and not get caught. This
essay asks the question of why might a craftsman in the sixteenth
century, like the author-practitioner or his projected reader, want to
steal a print, copy it, and surreptitiously return it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_nebolsin_victoria_final-project_animal-rationality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_nebolsin_victoria_final-project_animal-rationality/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="animal-rationality-in-ms-fr-640">Animal Rationality in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Victoria Nebolsin&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Making and Knowing: Hands-On History&lt;/p>
&lt;p>May 2022&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/">Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/a> reveals
a surprisingly symbolic treatment of some of the animals with which the
author-practitioner engages. While overall the manuscript possesses a
mostly practical, straightforward approach, several passages on animals
display language that sings with metaphor. Snakes are explicitly
compared to Satan (fol.
&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/109v/tl">109v&lt;/a>),
rats are compared to the tyrant of Syracuse
&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/152r/f/152r/tl">152r&lt;/a>),
and pigs can understand Greek
(&lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/13v/f/13v/tl">13v&lt;/a>).
The attention that the author-practitioner allots to animals only
amplifies the perplexing nature of these remarks. As Pamela Smith
underscores:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_wei-yang_jianing-luxi_popup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp22_wei-yang_jianing-luxi_popup/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="making-and-knowing-pop-up-book">Making and Knowing Pop-up Book&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Luxi Yang and Jianing Wei&lt;br/>
Spring 2022&lt;br/>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;iframe title="vimeo-player" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/710444936?h=b9508dad89" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;br/>&lt;br/>
&lt;a href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/documents/pdf/sp22_wei-yang_jianing-luxi_popup-presentation.pdf">A Visual Presentation of the Pop-up Book (PDF)&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/media-wei-yang/image1.png" alt="IMAGE">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="behind-the-scenes">Behind the scenes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This final project for the course &amp;ldquo;Making and Knowing in Early Modern
Europe: Hands-On History&amp;rdquo; at Columbia University was created by Luxi
Yang and Jianing Wei.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This pop-up book contains both a selection of entries from Ms. Fr. 640
and a miniaturized &lt;em>Kunstkammer&lt;/em>. Its four chapters &amp;ldquo;Tools and the
Book,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Life and Nature,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Nature and Imagination,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Against
Nature&amp;rdquo; emphasize the first-person and experimental nature of Ms. Fr.
640. The book as a whole reveals how Naturalia (natural things),
Artificialia (artifacts - human-made things), and Scientifica
(measuring/mathematical objects) were brought together in Renaissance
France to form intriguing collections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown-reece_final-project_dye-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown-reece_final-project_dye-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dyeing-textiles-with-cochineal">Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Reece Brown&lt;br>
Spring 2023&lt;br>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>My project takes the form of a workshop that teaches the process of dyeing to a group of 10 high school students. This endeavor promotes hands-on artisanal production that connects materials to their effects, integrating the different stages in the process into the different forms that the materials assume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This workshop explores cochineal from three different disciplines: biology, chemistry, and history. We will begin by discussing its life cycle and habitat, then pivot to focus on the particular compound for which it is known, i.e., carminic acid. The flow of this lesson follows the transformation of materials during the process of dyeing, turning cochineal from a resource to a material to a product. Every step in the “recipe” will be contextualized briefly prior to the hands-on endeavor, then more fully explored in a conversation as we wait for the materials to heat to the proper temperature. This outline lets the process and material reality come first, then provides more abstract information once students have oriented themselves in the world around them. It also provides productive instruction time during periods of stasis integrated throughout the process of dyeing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown_reece_final-project_dye-workshop-instructor-lab-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown_reece_final-project_dye-workshop-instructor-lab-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dyeing-textiles-with-cochineal">Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="lab-guide-for-instructors">Lab Guide for Instructors&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Reece Brown&lt;br>
Spring 2023&lt;br>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/media-brown/image4.png" alt="IMAGE">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="plant-based-dyes-the-chemistry-of-cochineal">Plant Based Dyes: The Chemistry of Cochineal&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This workshop was created to teach the process of dyeing to a group of
high school students in an environmental science class. This workshop
promotes hands-on artisanal production and helps students see the
various effects and uses of natural materials, showing how the different
stages in the process bring about different forms of the material.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown_reece_final-project_dye-workshop-student-lab-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_brown_reece_final-project_dye-workshop-student-lab-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dyeing-textiles-with-cochineal">Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="lab-guide-for-students">Lab Guide for Students&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Reece Brown&lt;br>
Spring 2023&lt;br>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;br>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Adapted from chapter 5, “Recipes,” of Jo Kirby et al, &lt;em>Natural Colorants
for Dyeing and Lake Pigments: Practical Recipes and their Historical
Sources&lt;/em> (Archetype, London, 2014).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="materials">MATERIALS&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Dyestuff (cochineal)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>mordant (alum)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Mortar and pestle&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Coffee filter&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Water&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Textile - 25 g cotton bandana&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Thermometer&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Stirring stick&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Plate&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_fan_ruilin_final-project_flesh-color/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_fan_ruilin_final-project_flesh-color/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="flesh-color-and-race-making-in-early-modern-painters-manuals">“Flesh Color” and Race Making in Early Modern Painters’ Manuals&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ruilin Fan&lt;br/>
Spring 2023&lt;br/>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>BnF Ms. Fr. 640 contains a number of recipes for making pigments and
paints. Among them, the author-practitioner is especially interested in
“flesh color (&lt;em>carnation&lt;/em>),” providing 18 entries that mention this
category of colors. It is evident from the diverse instructions
contained in these recipes that flesh color is not a singular skin tone
but refers to a range of colors that may represent various human
complexions. This essay is concerned with the ways in which the concept
of “flesh color” engaged with the understandings of race and ethnicity
in the author-practitioner’s early modern Toulouse, at a time when
European colonial enterprises continued to expand in the Atlantic world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_lambert-avery_final-project_medieval-spirituality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_lambert-avery_final-project_medieval-spirituality/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="medieval-spirituality-and-materiality-in-ms-fr-640">Medieval Spirituality and Materiality in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Avery Lambert&lt;br/>
Spring 2023&lt;br/>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The author-practitioner of Ms. Fr. 640 compiled his recipe-book in a
period of great religious, political, and social turmoil. Southern
France in the late sixteenth-century was a hotbed of conflict amidst the
Wars of Religion, during which competing religious ideas challenged
older beliefs and traditions. But where in this early modern world, and
in Ms. Fr. 640, can we find traces of earlier religious ritual
practices? An exploration of medieval spirituality and materiality
offers a framework by which to understand the manuscript’s distinctive
recipe for a burn salve and provides a glimpse of the medieval past in
the early modern workshop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_narcy_gilles_final-project_languages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_narcy_gilles_final-project_languages/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="languages-and-linguistic-agency-in-ms-fr-640">Languages and Linguistic Agency in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Gilles Narcy&lt;br/>
Spring 2023&lt;br/>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;br/>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="introduction-languages-as-practical-knowledge">Introduction: Languages as practical knowledge&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This essay focuses on the role played by languages in Ms. Fr. 640.
Although written in French, as its call number in the Bibliothèque
nationale de France’s catalogue indicates, it contains several
occurrences of other languages. Extensive scholarship has been dedicated
to artisan authors and the rise of books of recipes in the early modern
era, focusing on the difficulties and paradoxes of putting embodied,
practical knowledge into writing.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> The perspective adopted in this
essay is to approach writing, and more specifically the use of different
languages in various contexts, as a skill and a practical process
itself. My main contention, drawn from sociolinguistics, is that
languages, rather than neutral and substitutable vehicles for
communication, carry different meanings and implications in and of
themselves. They coexist and define themselves in relation to each other
inside a social space that can be described alternatively as an
ecology&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> or as a market&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. The use of each language produces
precise textual effects in the manuscript, whether they are purposely
intended by the author-practitioner or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_nelkin-nesya_final-project_candles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_nelkin-nesya_final-project_candles/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="candles-making-and-breaking-boundaries-in-early-modern-jewish-and-christian-ritual">Candles: Making and Breaking Boundaries in Early Modern Jewish and Christian Ritual&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nesya Nelkin&lt;br/>
Spring 2023&lt;br/>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Candles and their materials are ubiquitous in BnF Ms. Fr. 640. The author-practitioner suggests their use in activities as far-ranging as melting and cutting glass, smoking molds, to burning off small hairs from animals to be life-cast, to catching birds.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Beeswax and tallow (made by rendering suet, the organ fat of beef, lamb, or mutton), both very versatile substances and common candle materials, appear even more frequently, for purposes including molding, healing, food preservation, and portraiture.&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> The author-practitioner hints only obliquely at sacramental uses of wax,&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and makes no mention of the ritual functions of tallow or candles themselves. However, his concern for the material properties and artisanal uses of wax, tallow, and candles cannot be read outside of a broader context in which these materials and objects were associated with a complex range of theological and symbolic meanings. This paper discusses the ritual uses of wax and tallow candles among Jews and Christians in early modern Europe, focusing specifically on the ways that candles served to establish, mediate, and break down boundaries between spaces, times, and religious communities, and on the particular significance of candles in the ritual lives of women.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_oberem-lukas_final-project_varnish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_oberem-lukas_final-project_varnish/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="varnishing-a-craft-of-closure">Varnishing, a Craft of Closure&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lukas Oberem&lt;br/>
Spring 2023&lt;br/>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Le vernis racoustre tout cela &amp;amp; lunist &amp;amp; rend semblable aulta(n)t en un endroit quen laultre.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The varnish mends all this and unites and renders it similar in one place as in another.&lt;/em>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As a very last step, an artisan adds varnish to a work of craft. With this small addition, we may say, the work receives its last touch. This seemingly simple fact of coating an object with varnish opens up many questions about the structural importance of finalizing an artisanal and artistic work. Varnish perfects the appearance of a work and preserves it with a thin film of oil and resin. By a finger meticulously rubbed over a painting or with a brush applied to a plank, varnish coats glass and metal, wood, and canvas. Especially in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, everything can and is potentially covered in varnish. Among a wide variety of recipes in medieval and Renaissance manuscripts, we find a great number for varnish. For instance, up to twenty percent of entries in Ms. Fr. 640 deal with the production and use of varnish.&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Ms. Fr. 640 is one of many examples that account for the variety and importance of varnish in the late sixteenth century. Why is varnish so important in the processes of art and craft making? What are the structural implications of varnish being a very last step of a work?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_rao-sumant_final-project_puffball/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_rao-sumant_final-project_puffball/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="puffball-mushrooms-and-early-modern-race-making-a-skin-whitening-recipe-in-bnf-ms-fr-640">Puffball Mushrooms and Early Modern Race-Making: A Skin-Whitening Recipe in BnF Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sumant Rao&lt;br/>
Spring 2023&lt;br/>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In Thomas Heywood’s and Richard Brome’s play &lt;em>The Late Lancashire Witches&lt;/em> (1634), a wedding party is awaiting an extravagant banquet; suddenly, after the host reads out the menu, a woman runs on stage and exclaims that their feast has undergone a horrible transformation:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_shi-jingxian_final-project_paintbrushes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/sp23_shi-jingxian_final-project_paintbrushes/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="european-paintbrushes-and-chinese-ink-brushes-in-the-early-modern-world">European Paintbrushes and Chinese Ink Brushes in the Early Modern World&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Jingxian Shi&lt;br/>
Spring 2023&lt;br/>
HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Chinese ink brushes have become inextricably intertwined with writing culture, evolving into a symbol of literacy and the mastery of Chinese characters. Some scholars assert that the Chinese ink brush is unique as the only soft-tip brush in existence in the early modern period. This claim is challenged by the presence of similarly structured soft-tip paintbrushes in European societies, characteristically having a slender brush tube with an animal hair tuft. Records of making soft-tip brushes can be found in the fifteenth-century Italian manuscript &lt;em>Il Libro dell’Arte&lt;/em> by Cennino Cennini (known as &lt;em>The Craftsman’s Handbook&lt;/em> in English) and the sixteenth-century French manuscript BnF Ms. Fr. 640.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> While the structure and materials of the two implements share similarities, the ink brushes from China and paintbrushes from Europe exhibit variations under the hands of their users, catering to diverse writing and painting needs and further reinforcing differences in Chinese and European writing and painting habits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_branscum_elizabeth_final-project-medicinal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_branscum_elizabeth_final-project-medicinal/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="medicine-in-ms-fr-640-and-household-recipe-books">Medicine in Ms. Fr. 640 and Household Recipe Books&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Elizabeth Branscum&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;em>Summer 2021&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you know by now, the origin and purpose of &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/">BnF Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/a> is still uncertain. Who is the mysterious author-practitioner who compiled these recipes, and what did he intend to do with them? Part of what makes this question so intriguing is the inclusion of recipes on such a wide variety of topics – craft, sleight of hand, and even medicine. The medical recipes in the manuscript are particularly curious. Out of over 900 entries, there are only 48 that explicitly detail medical recipes, and they are scattered throughout the manuscript with little apparent rhyme or reason. In this essay, I will look more closely at the medical entries in Ms. Fr. 640, and compare them briefly to medical recipes included in a household recipe book compiled in mid-seventeenth century England.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> This comparison, which places Ms. Fr. 640 alongside a text from a similar period whose purpose and genre is well-established, may shed light on the strategies and intent of the author-practitioner in compiling the medical recipes in Fr. 640, and raise fruitful questions for further study.&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_christensen_anna_final-project-natural-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_christensen_anna_final-project-natural-things/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="understanding-natural-things-in-the-world-and-the-workshop">Understanding Natural Things in the World and the Workshop&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Anna Christensen&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;em>Summer 2021&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lifecasting and preservation practices that appear in &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/">BnF Ms. Fr.
640&lt;/a> are a window into the understanding of the natural world through
craft practice during the sixteenth century. Animals that appear as
casts or natural historical specimens in the manuscript include frogs
and toads, snakes, lizards, turtles, flies, spiders, beetles, crabs,
crayfish, bats, rats, cats, and birds of various kinds. The attention
paid to these commonplace animals and their representation through craft
practices can shed light on the way nature was imagined and came to be
known during this period. Through certain choices the
author-practitioner makes around the posing, juxtaposition, and display
of his dried animal specimens and life casts, we can begin to get at his
attitude towards representing the natural. More than just seeking to
imitate the natural world, the author-practitioner’s craft reflects both
artistic considerations and attempts to understand how animals interact
with one another and with the world around them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_fox_mackenzie_final-project-disorganization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_fox_mackenzie_final-project-disorganization/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="was-ms-fr-640-intentionally-disorganized">Was Ms. Fr. 640 Intentionally Disorganized?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Mackenzie Fox&lt;/em>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;em>Summer 2021&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When browsing through the wide range of how-to instructions in &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/">BnF Ms. Fr.
640&lt;/a>, it is often frustratingly unclear why the author-practitioner chose
to address such disparate topics in a single text, or why he chose to
arrange them in such an apparently random way. Why, for instance, does
he, in the space of a single page, give advice on how to prepare earth
for making molds to cast metal, record an observation about the ways in
which garden lilies grow and flower, offer yet further advice on the
appropriate type of earth for use in casting, and, finally, discuss the
rate at which ducklings grow and how one should feed them?&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> (See image
below for the page in question, fol. &lt;a href="https://edition640.makingandknowing.org/#/folios/41r/f/41r/tl">41r&lt;/a>) Does he perceive a relationship
between the topics covered in these entries? Was he simply jotting down
information as it occurred to him as he went about his life? Was Ms. Fr.
640 a work in progress that the author intended to rearrange at a later
date before publication or wider
circulation?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_macomber_sophie_final-project-figures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su21_macomber_sophie_final-project-figures/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="pictures-worth-1000-words-figures-and-their-uses-in-ms-fr-640">Pictures Worth 1,000 Words: Figures and their Uses in Ms. Fr. 640&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Sophie Macomber&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Summer 2021&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you ever tried following a new recipe that didn't have any pictures? Not even a picture of the end result? It's hard, right?! While pictures might seem to add clutter when you're just trying to figure out how much water to add to four cups of flour or exactly to what temperature the oven needs to be set, they can be meaningful tools for communicating other kinds of information, and their use in instruction manuals and notebooks dates back centuries (see also Leonardo Da Vinci's notebooks for a contemporaneous example of the use of figures), as can be seen in Ms. Fr. 640, a sixteenth-century collection of practical techniques.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/student-projects/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="dyeing-with-onion-skins">Dyeing with Onion Skins&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Annika Cunningham, summer and fall 2022&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My name is Annika Cunningham, and I am a high schooler in Boston. I have
been weaving, knitting, and crocheting for over a decade, and also enjoy
exploring the scientific methods behind these crafts. I wanted to
experiment with dye-making techniques using more affordable and
accessible materials, like onion skins!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onions originated in Asia and the Middle East, but the exact period and
geographic origin are uncertain. Turkish artisans in the mid-1400s
started using onion skins to dye carpets and rugs. Additionally, many
artisans still use these methods to create authentic rugs today. Natural
Dyes were also used by early Navajo artisans, who are known for their
woven rugs and blankets. Many started using natural dyes in the 1700s
and, in Navajo weaver Mable Burnside-Myer’s Dye chart, she shows the use
of onion skins in her work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="hist-gu4962-making-and-knowing-in-early-modern-europe-hands-on-history">HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/images/media-syllabus-sp23-mk/image1.png" alt="IMAGE">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>HIST GU4962&lt;/strong>
&lt;strong>Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe:&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>Hands-On History&lt;/strong>
&lt;strong>Tuesdays 10:10am-12:00pm&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instructor&lt;/strong>:
Prof. Pamela Smith&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Assistant Director, Making and Knowing Project:&lt;/strong>
Naomi Rosenkranz&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Project and Communications Coordinator, Making and Knowing Project:&lt;/strong>
Caroline Surman&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is associated with the &lt;a href="http://www.makingandknowing.org/">&lt;u>Making and Knowing Project&lt;/u>&lt;/a> of the &lt;a href="http://scienceandsociety.columbia.edu/">&lt;u>Center for Science and Society&lt;/u>&lt;/a> at Columbia University. Please sign up for announcements for both on the websites!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>