<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reflections on Hands-On on Research and Teaching Companion</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/</link><description>Recent content in Reflections on Hands-On on Research and Teaching Companion</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2024, Columbia University</copyright><atom:link href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/bibliography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/bibliography/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="bibliography-for-hands-on-teaching-and-learning">Bibliography for Hands-On Teaching and Learning&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Almevik, Gunnar, Camilla Groth, and Tina Westerlund. Explorations in Craft Sciences. 2-18, 2022. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.21524/kriterium.40">https://doi.org/10.21524/kriterium.40&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beentjes, Tonny, and Pamela H. Smith. “Sixteenth-century life-casting techniques: experimental reconstructions based on a preserved manuscript.” In The Renaissance Workshop, edited by David Saunders, Marika Spring and Andrew Meek. London: Archetype Publications Ltd, 2013, 144-51.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bilak, Donna. “Out of the Ivy and into the Arctic: Imitation Coral Reconstruction in Cross-Cultural Contexts.” Berichte Zur Wissenschaftsgeschichte 43, no. 3 (2020): 341–66. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/bewi.202000010">https://doi.org/10.1002/bewi.202000010&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/uchacz-course-reflection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/reflection/uchacz-course-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="teaching-reflections-and-tips-from-texas-am---tianna-uchacz">Teaching Reflections and Tips from Texas A&amp;amp;M - Tianna Uchacz&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Tianna Uchacz served as Postdoctoral Scholar of the Making and Knowing Project 2016-2020, co-instructing M&amp;amp;K courses, developing hands-on activities, and fostering collaborations between diverse scholars, students, and practitioners. Since 2020, Tianna Uchacz is Assistant Professor of Art History at Texas A&amp;amp;M University. She has adapted existing courses to incorporate hands-on work and developed new classes with a dedicated focus on materials and the exploration of artistic proccess. Her notes and reflections are below, including ideas and logistics for scaling up activities and new instructional materials.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>