<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources in the Research and Teaching Companion on Research and Teaching Companion</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources in the Research and Teaching Companion on Research and Teaching Companion</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Columbia University</copyright><atom:link href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making &amp; Knowing Syllabi</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</guid><description>Making and Knowing Project Syllabi Syllabi from the Making and Knowing Project can be used to suggest possible readings, discussion prompts, model the integration of hands-on activities with seminar-style discussion of relevant concepts and texts, and connect instructors to resources for hands-on activities. These syllabi contain links to the edition&amp;rsquo;s approximately 130 essays which can be used as course readings or to instruct in reconstructions (also useful for this are field notes).</description></item><item><title>M&amp;K Resources in Use</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</guid><description>Making and Knowing Resources in Use The Making and Knowing Project has many collaborators from K-12 to university, to non-traditional schools and public outreach institutions, who have piloted the Making and Knowing Project&amp;rsquo;s methods, course elements, and lesson plans in their research projects, courses, and student activities. The fruits of their experience, their syllabi, student projects, and making activities are valuable for those seeking to integrate Making and Knowing resources into their teaching and research.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</guid><description>HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History HIST GU4962 Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History Tuesdays 10:10am-12:00pm
Instructor: Prof. Pamela Smith
Assistant Director, Making and Knowing Project: Naomi Rosenkranz
Project and Communications Coordinator, Making and Knowing Project: Caroline Surman
This course is associated with the Making and Knowing Project of the Center for Science and Society at Columbia University. Please sign up for announcements for both on the websites!</description></item></channel></rss>