<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on Research and Teaching Companion</title><link>https://teaching640.makingandknowing.org/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on Research and Teaching Companion</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Columbia University</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://teaching640.makingandknowing.org/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Syllabi</title><link>https://teaching640.makingandknowing.org/resources/syllabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teaching640.makingandknowing.org/resources/syllabi/</guid><description>HIST GR8906: Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World Columbia University, History Department, graduate-level &amp;ldquo;Lab Seminar&amp;rdquo;
This Lab Seminar course studies the materials, techniques, settings, and meanings of skilled craft and artistic practices in the early modern period (1350-1750), in order to reflect upon a series of issues, including craft knowledge and artisanal epistemology; the intersections between craft and science; and questions of historical methodology and evidence in the reconstruction of historical experience.</description></item><item><title>Case Studies</title><link>https://teaching640.makingandknowing.org/resources/case-studies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://teaching640.makingandknowing.org/resources/case-studies/</guid><description>Collaborator Pilot Courses Materials from courses taught by Project collaborators, some using resources from this Sandbox or developed in consultation with M&amp;amp;K.
Spring 2022: ARTH 295 (OC): Ingenious Making in the Early Modern World [Syllabus] Spring 2022 Oberlin College Professor Christina Neilson, Associate Professor of Art History
Course description: This course investigates what it meant to make things and work with materials, including featherwork, imitation gems, color making, and metal casting, in Europe and colonial Latin America between around 1350 and 1650.</description></item></channel></rss>