<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on Research and Teaching Companion</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on Research and Teaching Companion</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Columbia University</copyright><atom:link href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making and Knowing Syllabi</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</guid><description>The Making and Knowing Project began teaching courses that integrated hands-on activities in 2014. In the course Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World—taught 2014-18—graduate students conducted text-, object-, and laboratory-based research that resulted in the edition&amp;rsquo;s approximately 130 essays which interpret, contextualize, and reconstruct the content of Ms. Fr. 640. The Companion contains syllabi for each of the eight versions of Craft and Science, focused each year on a different theme: Moldmaking and Metalworking; Colormaking (including dyes, pigments, artificial gems, coloring woods and metals, and varnish making); Practical Knowledge: Vernacular Natural History, Practical Perspective, Optics, Mechanics, and Medicine; Ephemeral Art; and Printmaking, Inscription, and Impression.</description></item><item><title>Using M&amp;K Resources</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</guid><description>The Making and Knowing Project has collaborated with many institutions, including University of Glasgow Technical Art History Group, Rhode Island School of Design Glass Department, Brown University History Department, Wake Forest University History and Chemistry Departments [LINK], University of Oregon, Eugene {LINK], Vassar College [LINK], Texas A&amp;amp;M University, and Oberlin Art History {LINK]. Further collaborations with Victoria &amp;amp; Albert Museum/Royal College of Art Postgraduate Program in the History of Design [, and University of Amsterdam Technical Art History and Conservation Training Programs saw our students working in parallel and sometimes by remote co-working on reconstructions and hands-on activities.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</guid><description>HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History HIST GU4962 Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History Tuesdays 10:10am-12:00pm
Instructor: Prof. Pamela Smith
Assistant Director, Making and Knowing Project: Naomi Rosenkranz
Project and Communications Coordinator, Making and Knowing Project: Caroline Surman
This course is associated with the Making and Knowing Project of the Center for Science and Society at Columbia University. Please sign up for announcements for both on the websites!</description></item></channel></rss>