<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Resources on Research and Teaching Companion</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/</link><description>Recent content in Resources on Research and Teaching Companion</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Columbia University</copyright><atom:link href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making and Knowing Syllabi</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/</guid><description>The Making and Knowing Project taught hands-on courses from 2014. Where students in the course Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World, taught 2014-18, conducted text-, object-, and laboratory-based research that resulted in essays included in the edition, our students in Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History, taught since 2021, explored Secrets of Craft and Nature to create projects—involving all kinds of research—that extend the content of the edition in creative and sometimes surprising ways.</description></item><item><title>Using Making and Knowing Resources</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/case-studies/</guid><description>The Making and Knowing Project has collaborated with many institutions, including University of Glasgow Technical Art History Group, Rhode Island School of Design Glass Department, Brown University History Department, Wake Forest University History and Chemistry Departments [LINK], University of Oregon, Eugene {LINK], Vassar College [LINK], Texas A&amp;amp;M University, and Oberlin Art History {LINK]. Further collaborations with Victoria &amp;amp; Albert Museum/Royal College of Art Postgraduate Program in the History of Design [, and University of Amsterdam Technical Art History and Conservation Training Programs saw our students working in parallel and sometimes by remote co-working on reconstructions and hands-on activities.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/syllabi/syllabus_sp23_gu4962-hands-on-history/</guid><description>HIST GU4962 Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History Tuesdays 10:10am-12:00pm
Instructor: Prof. Pamela Smith
Assistant Director, Making and Knowing Project: Naomi Rosenkranz
Project and Communications Coordinator, Making and Knowing Project: Caroline Surman
This course is associated with the Making and Knowing Project of the Center for Science and Society at Columbia University. Please sign up for announcements for both on the websites!
DESCRIPTION This course introduces students to the materials, techniques, contexts, and meanings of skilled craft and artistic practices in early modern Europe (1350-1750), in order to reflect upon a series of topics, including craft knowledge and artisanal epistemology; the intersections between craft and science; and questions of historical methodology in studying the material world of the past.</description></item></channel></rss>