<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lesson Plans for Hands-on on Research and Teaching Companion</title><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/</link><description>Recent content in Lesson Plans for Hands-on on Research and Teaching Companion</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2022, Columbia University</copyright><atom:link href="https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_dyeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_dyeing/</guid><description>Dyeing The Making and Knowing Project has undertaken experiments in dyeing with natural colorants as a way to engage with various entries in Ms. Fr. 640 and as a preliminary step to making lake pigments. Additionally, M&amp;amp;K has led several community outreach activites on dyeing with natural colorants that can be ported directly into the classroom. These activities and their contexts are also described on the Making and Knowing Resources in Use section of the Companion.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-historical-recipe-collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-historical-recipe-collection/</guid><description>Guide to historical recipes and collections There are far more sources available in online library collections that you may wish to use instead, below is a sample of sources we found useful in Making and Knowing classes.
We also recommend scouring your institutional library’s holdings for historical items related to food and recipes.
Sources in English Wellcome Ms. 213: A Booke of diuers Medecines, Broothes, Salues, Waters, Syroppes and Oyntementes of which many or the most part haue been experienced and tryed by the speciall practize of Mrs Corlyon.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-instructor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-instructor/</guid><description>Historical Culinary Recipe Reconstruction Cooking is an almost universal activity – it is an art, a craft, a science – and yet most people do it without categorizing it as such. Cooking can provide a way for instructors to introduce hands-on experiments and close textual analysis to their students, many of whom will be used to following instructions from recipes and may feel more comfortable engaging in a hands-on activity in a kitchen than a studio, lab, or classroom.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-student/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_hcr-student/</guid><description>Historical Culinary Recipe Reconstruction – Student Activity Sheet Do the required reading and watching before you start your reconstruction. Explore and use the websites listed here to search for comparable recipes in contemporaneous sources.
Required Reading/Watching/Listening (do this first) Ken Albala, “Cooking as Research Methodology: Experiments in Renaissance Cuisine,” Renaissance Food from Rabelais to Shakespeare: Culinary Readings and Culinary Histories, ed. Joan Fitzpatrick (Aldershot, UK: Ashgate, 2010), pp. 73–88.
Syrup of Violets and Science video (ca 8 mins).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_inks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_inks/</guid><description>Making Inks The Making and Knowing Project has reconstructed inks several times, both as products and as ingredients in more complex making processes described in Ms. Fr. 640. While the manuscript is itself written in iron gall ink (the &amp;ldquo;common&amp;rdquo; black writing ink of the Renaissance), it does not include any writing ink recipes. Learning about and making writing inks can thus shed light on the history and materiality of texts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_jasper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_jasper/</guid><description>Counterfeit Jasper MS Fr. 640 contains just one entry about jasper, early in the manuscript, on fol.10r. Under an entry entitled “Counterfeit jasper”, the author-practitioner instructs:
Take horn from which one makes lanterns, quite thin, &amp;amp; underneath make the figure of your jasper, cornalines, &amp;amp; other stones, which will be a work more appropriate than on glass, which is too shiny. And the horn presents a luster &amp;amp; fatty polish like jasper.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_lake-pigments/</guid><description>Making Lake Pigments The Making and Knowing Project has used lake pigment making as a core skill-building exercise for its students. M&amp;amp;K has often assigned lake pigment making alongside verdigris growing, which were then followed up by a paint making and testing activity. Nevertheless, lake pigment making can be done on its own.
Learning Objectives The activity of making lake pigments from modernized historical recipes has several potential learning outcomes, which can include:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_paintingpigments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_paintingpigments/</guid><description>Making and Testing Paints Made by Hand from Pigments The Making and Knowing Project has used paint and test card making as a core skill-building exercise for its students. Paint making has often been a follow-up activity to lake pigment making or verdigris growing, but paint making can also be undertaken using commercially produced pigments.
Learning Objectives The activity of making paint and testing out those paints on a sample card has several potential learning outcomes, which can include:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_reconstruction-template-sample/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_reconstruction-template-sample/</guid><description>Reconstruction Template Sample This was compiled by students from discussions of their reconstruction experience. It is shared here not as a model for you to follow, but as an example of the kinds of responses that you might receive from students when they are asked to reflect on how to conduct reconstruction experiments.
Projected Outcome What are the goals of your reconstruction?
What historical question are you trying to answer?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_sample-hcr-discussion-document/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_sample-hcr-discussion-document/</guid><description>SAMPLE: Historical Culinary Reconstruction Discussion Document nb. These are real, unedited, student comments. This document is shared to give you a sense of the kinds of responses this activity can elicit. Names have been redacted.
STUDENT A– One thing that stuck out to me throughout our recipe reconstructions was the frustration of vague instructions - what does “a large quantity of water” mean? What does it mean to prepare something “as beforehand”?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_stucco/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_stucco/</guid><description>Making Stucco for Molding The Making and Knowing Project has reconstructed variants of a recipe for &amp;ldquo;stucco for molding,&amp;rdquo; as described in BnF Ms. Fr. 640. This recipe uses tragacanth gum and either chalk or rye flour to produce a paste that can take on quite detailed shapes in simple molds (wood, metal, silicone) and that is very hard once dry. This activity is cheap, easy, and relatively safe to undertake with a variety of learners.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_suggestions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_suggestions/</guid><description>Suggestions for Additional Lesson Plans</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_supportsurfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_supportsurfaces/</guid><description>Preparing Panels, Canvases, and Other Supports for Painting, Gilding, etc. Images: Preparing a canvas for painting.
This activity teaches students how to prepare common supports, namely panels and canvases, to receive paint. The preparations outlined below ensure that any media applied to the support goes on evenly without risk of bleeding into or through that support. This activity can be undertaken as a stand-alone skill-building exercise or it can be a prelude to paint making and testing using hand-made lake pigments, hand-grown verdigris, and/or hand-levigated azurite.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_varnishes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/activitysheet_varnishes/</guid><description>Making Varnishes The Making and Knowing Project has reconstructed varnish recipes several times, both as products and as ingredients in more complex making processes described in Ms. Fr. 640. The manuscript includes several recipes for spirit varnishes, which were a new category of varnish that emerged in the sixteenth century. It also includes several recipes for oil-based varnishes, which have a longer history and are quite dangerous to reconstruct and often result in fires.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/azurite-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/azurite-assignment/</guid><description>Skillbuilding: Preparing and Painting with Azurite The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2022-11-30 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Presentations &amp;amp; Handouts Presentation: Preparing and Painting Blue Pigment in the Renaissance See also a short version of this presentation Student Handout (to have while doing the hands-on reconstruction) Introduction This skillbuilding assignment will introduce you to one of the most common blue pigments in the Renaissance, azurite.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding-student-activity-sheet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding-student-activity-sheet/</guid><description>Class Activity: Making and Molding Bread Objectives explore historical breadmaking recipes and techniques
learn to bake bread
produce loaves of bread to use as molds
This activity has two parts
Part 1 (at home before class): learn to bake bread and produce loaves to use as molds for a small object
Part 2 (in class): pour wax (and/or sulfur) into your molds, unmold
Source text There are two entries on breadmolding on fol.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding_resources-for-the-instructor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/breadmolding_resources-for-the-instructor/</guid><description>Bread Making, Molding, and Casting (for the Instructor) Introduction The sixteenth-century artisanal/technical manual, BnF Ms. Fr. 640, contains hundreds of entries that describe making processes and techniques from the Renaissance. These include instructions for and observations about painting, gilding, arms and armor production, plant cultivation, and making molds and metal casts.
Ms. Fr. 640 contains three mentions of bread as a material that can be used to take an impression of another object quickly and neatly.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/burnsalve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/burnsalve/</guid><description>Activity: Reconstruction of a 16th-Century Burn Salve Recipe The study of historical recipes or &amp;ldquo;how-to&amp;rdquo; instructions can be a powerful tool to engage with the past and to learn about daily life in a different, more tangible way than traditional textual sources. Historical reconstruction &amp;ndash; attempting to follow or replicate the recipe &amp;ndash; can bring the past to life and provide new perspectives for experts and students alike.
The activity sheet and resources below are intended to invite you to undertake a hands-on historical reconstruction yourself, or to provide you with what you will need to bring this activity into your classroom, studio, or even kitchen.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-assignment/</guid><description>Dyeing with Natural Colorants: Resources and Activity Sheets Resources for dyeing textiles with natural colorants (including cochineal, madder, weld, and redwoods) following historical dye recipes. Recipes and procedure adapted from Jo Kirby et al, Natural Colorants for Dyeing and Lake Pigments: Practical Recipes and their Historical Sources (Archetype, London, 2014) (2022-06-17)
Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation - an overview of historical natural colorants and dyes, details about common red colorants, a deep-dive into the history of cochineal insects as a dye and pigment source, the preparation of mordant dyes, and explanation of the chemistry of these natural colorants</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-cochineal_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/dyes-cochineal_assignment/</guid><description>Dyeing Textiles with Cochineal: A Historical Reconstruction The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2023-03-30 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Dyes and natural colorants If you are not already familiar with historical dyes and natural colorants, refer to Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation for more complete information and further explanation of natural colorants and dyeing.
A dye is &amp;ldquo;a compound that absorbs into and colors another material&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;is generally a complex organic material&amp;rdquo; (Conservation and Art Materials Encyclopedia Online (CAMEO)).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/painting-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/painting-assignment/</guid><description>Making Paints from Pigments and Painting Them Out HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-05-13 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Paint = Pigment + Binding Media Refer to Presentation: Introduction to Pigments &amp;amp; Paints
Overview of Activity Much more detailed information and resources are provided below in this document. To help get you started, this is an overview of the hands-on work and preparation you will do:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-cochineal-lake_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-cochineal-lake_assignment/</guid><description>MAKING LAKE PIGMENT FROM COCHINEAL: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-09-29 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Lake pigments and natural colorants If you are not already familiar with historical pigments and natural colorants, refer to Presentation: Cochineal Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation for more complete information and further explanation of natural colorants and lake pigments.
See also Presentation: Introduction to Pigments &amp;amp; Paints.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-madder-lake_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/pigment-madder-lake_assignment/</guid><description>MAKING LAKE PIGMENT WITH MADDER: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2022-01-29 by NJR
Refer also to:
Presentation: Madder Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation - while this is for a different colorant (cochineal), the chemistry of lakes is the same. Making Pigment from Madder: a Trio of Recipes - helpful step-by-step fieldnotes for all three recipes Lake pigments are a type of pigment prepared from organic natural colorants: plant and animal sources.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt-2/</guid><description>Secrets of Craft and Nature Reconnaissance (Directed Scavenger Hunt) A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
BnF Ms. Fr. 640 has 170 folios (340 pages) with over 900 entries on metalworking, casting, painting, medicine, and sleight of hand tricks. This is an exercise with two activities to help become familiar with the online Edition and Translation of Ms. Fr. 640: Secrets of Craft and Nature.
Activity 1: Explore the Manuscript Folios Choose a linked folio from below and find:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt_secrets-of-craft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/scavenger-hunt_secrets-of-craft/</guid><description>Scavenger Hunt: Get to know Secrets of Craft and Nature Browse the online Edition of Ms. Fr. 640: Secrets of Craft and Nature.
Explore each menu item.
Complete the scavenger hunt of the Edition
Pick three of the following terms (or another term of your choosing), and use the search bar to search the manuscript: &amp;ldquo;mercury,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;bread,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;rat,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;dog,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;cuttlefish,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;saliva,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;garlic,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;blood,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;rosemary,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;milk,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;horse,” “earwax” Browse the results and select one of the occurrences in the manuscript that you find interesting.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp22_fld_rosenkranz_naomi_madder-lake-trio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp22_fld_rosenkranz_naomi_madder-lake-trio/</guid><description>MAKING LAKE PIGMENT WITH MADDER: A HISTORICAL RECONSTRUCTION The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2022-01-29 by NJR
Refer (insert something like &amp;ldquo;refer to the assignment sheet&amp;rdquo; instead of what&amp;rsquo;s here, keep jo kirby info though) also to Presentation: Cochineal Lake: History, Chemistry, and Preparation - while this is for a different colorant (cochineal), the chemistry of lakes is the same. (this was an experiment to try all three different recipes, each of which is listed below)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp23_dyes_tamu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/sp23_dyes_tamu/</guid><description>BioArt Workshop: Dyeing with Cochineal Bugs The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2023-03-24 by NJR
Texas A&amp;amp;M PVFA/BIOL BioArt Workshop March 21–24, 2023 Organized by Tianna Uchacz with Donna Janes and Naomi Rosenkranz
Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation Presentation: Cochineal Dye: History, Chemistry, and Preparation
Handouts Dyeing Instructions - General Process for Mordanting and Dyeing Textiles Summary of Dye Samples and Measurements Recipe Example: De&amp;rsquo; secreti del reverendo signore Alessio Piemontese (1558) Summary of Materials and Samples Name Mordant Dye NC None Cochineal NCP None Cochineal + potash AC Alum Cochineal ACP Alum Cochineal + potash IC Iron sulphate Cochineal CC Copper sulphate Cochineal Textiles</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco-assignment/</guid><description>STUCCO FOR MOLDING RECONSTRUCTION HIST GR8906: Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World | Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-09-24 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
NOTE TO INSTRUCTORS: Rather than providing the full instructions, one may want to provide students only with the original recipe and the materials, allowing them to interpret the entry for themselves.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco_assignment_student-handout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/stucco_assignment_student-handout/</guid><description>STUCCO FOR MOLDING RECONSTRUCTION - STUDENT HANDOUT HIST GR8906: Craft and Science: Making Objects in the Early Modern World | Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-09-24 by NJR
Ephemeral Art in BnF Ms. Fr. 640 The 16th-century artisanal/technical manual, BnF Ms. Fr. 640, contains hundreds of entries that describe making processes and techniques from the Renaissance. These include instructions for and observations about painting, gilding, arms and armor production, plant cultivation, and making molds and metal casts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su17_rosenkranz_azurite-preparation-cambridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su17_rosenkranz_azurite-preparation-cambridge/</guid><description>June 5, 2017
Azurite crushing and washing session
Led by Spike Bucklow
Fitzwilliam studio room
Notes by NJR (Naomi Rosenkranz)
Flickr album of&amp;gt; Azurite_NJR
V&amp;amp;A/RCA blog post on Azurite May 2017 part&amp;gt; 1
V&amp;amp;A/RCA blog post on Azurite May 2017 part&amp;gt; 2
Cambridge University
“Genius Before Romanticism”
Workshop organized by the Ingenuity Project (Alex Marr) with the Making Visible Project (S. Kusukawa) and the curatorial team of the Fitzwilliam Museum’s “Madonnas and Miracles” exhibit (March - June 2017)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/su22_fld_cunningham_annika_onion-skin-dyeing/</guid><description>Dyeing with Onion Skins Annika Cunningham, summer and fall 2021
Introduction My name is Annika Cunningham, and I am a high schooler in Boston. I have been weaving, knitting, and crocheting for over a decade, and also enjoy exploring the scientific methods behind these crafts. I wanted to experiment with dye-making techniques using more affordable and accessible materials, like onion skins!
Onions originated in Asia and the Middle East, but the exact period and geographic origin are uncertain.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/varnish-sourcing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/varnish-sourcing/</guid><description>varnish sourcing</description></item><item><title/><link>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cu-mkp.github.io/research-teaching-companion/resources/activity-sheets/verdigris-assignment/</guid><description>VERDIGRIS PIGMENT &amp;ldquo;GROWING&amp;rdquo; RECONSTRUCTION HIST GU4962: Making and Knowing in Early Modern Europe: Hands-On History
The Making and Knowing Project, Columbia University
Last updated 2021-08-19 by NJR
A downloadable version of this assignment: [PDF]
Safety Note: Nitrile/latex gloves must be worn when handling verdigris. Do not touch your mouth or bare skin. Do not scrape or grind the verdigris on food preparation surfaces.
Verdigris is a blue-green pigment prepared by exposing copper to acetic acid (vinegar), forming a basic copper acetate.</description></item></channel></rss>